<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>fusion94.org</title>
    <description>Totally Random Musings from the Edge</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 13:56:45 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 13:56:45 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Benchy&apos;s Gone Wild</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;3dbenchy-remix-takedowns-stir-controversy-on-printables&quot;&gt;3DBenchy Remix Takedowns Stir Controversy on Printables&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remixes of the iconic 3DBenchy model are being removed from
&lt;a href=&quot;https://printables.com&quot;&gt;Printables&lt;/a&gt;, a 3D printing file-sharing platform
operated by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.prusa3d.com/&quot;&gt;Prusa Research&lt;/a&gt;. This enforcement
highlights longstanding but previously unenforced licensing restrictions tied to
the design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 3DBenchy, a popular benchmarking model for FDM 3D printers, has been
licensed under &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nd/4.0/&quot;&gt;Creative Commons BY-ND
4.0&lt;/a&gt; since its release in 2015.
This license prohibits redistribution of derivative works. However, Creative
Tools, the model’s creator, had not enforced these restrictions, allowing
remixed versions to circulate freely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Concerns arose recently when Reddit user u/mkrjoe shared a Printables customer
support message stating all derivative Benchy models would be removed. The user
reported their remix, titled “My Benchy Glitched Out,” was deleted, sparking
widespread community backlash. Many makers expressed frustration in online
forums, criticizing the crackdown on reimagined versions of the beloved design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The situation follows Creative Tools’ acquisition by NTI Group in March 2024.
This Denmark-based digital solutions provider now holds intellectual property
rights to 3DBenchy, fueling speculation that NTI initiated the takedowns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, NTI’s Chief Marketing Officer, Henriette Tamasauskas, denied this,
telling 3D Printing Industry that NTI “has not taken any action to enforce the
3DBenchy license or remove derivatives.” Prusa Research CMO Rudolf Krčmář
confirmed that Printables had acted in response to a “third-party report” but
clarified that NTI was not the source of the complaint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Krčmář explained that Printables’ actions aligned with its policy of adhering to
licensing terms. “Standard procedure” required the removal of remixed Benchy
files due to the non-derivative clause of the BY-ND 4.0 license. He added that
discussions with NTI are ongoing, with both parties exploring options to address
the community’s concerns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“NTI has expressed support for keeping remixes of the Benchy model available,”
Krčmář shared, suggesting that an amendment to the license could enable remixing
in the future. Tamasauskas emphasized NTI’s lack of intent to monetize 3DBenchy
and pledged to review potential solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Daniel Norée, 3DBenchy’s lead designer, bid farewell to Creative
Tools in a reflective &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7282680313879683072/&quot;&gt;LinkedIn post&lt;/a&gt; following the company’s merger with NTI.
Describing Creative Tools as a once “great company,” Norée lamented its
dissolution and expressed gratitude for its role in the 3D printing community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;intellectual-property-in-the-maker-space&quot;&gt;Intellectual Property in the Maker Space&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 3DBenchy controversy underscores broader tensions between intellectual
property laws and the open-source ethos central to the maker community. While
Creative Commons licensing has facilitated the sharing of 3D-printable designs,
restrictive terms like the BY-ND 4.0 license challenge the free remix culture
embraced by many hobbyists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Adrian Bowyer, founder of the RepRap project and a pioneer of open-source 3D
printing, has dismissed intellectual property protections as “nonsense upon
stilts.” Conversely, Michael Weinberg, a board member of the Open Source
Hardware Association (OSHWA), has praised Creative Commons licenses for enabling
a proliferation of publicly available 3D models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite these benefits, licensing disputes in 3D printing are not new. In 2019,
Lego issued takedown notices targeting 3D-printed replicas of its products,
including fan art and scaled-up versions of iconic designs. Similarly, Honda
enforced intellectual property claims against Prusa Research in 2022, leading to
the removal of Honda-related files from Printables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the maker community grapples with the complexities of intellectual property,
the ongoing discussions between NTI and Prusa Research may offer a precedent for
balancing creativity, collaboration, and legal compliance in the future of 3D
printing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 04:32:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025/01/25/benchys/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025/01/25/benchys/</guid>
        
        <category>3d printing</category>
        
        <category>prusa</category>
        
        <category>makers</category>
        
        <category>3d-Printing</category>
        
        <category>printables</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>AMS Humidity Control</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;bambu-labs-automatic-material-system-and-the-importance-of-humidity-control&quot;&gt;Bambu Lab’s Automatic Material System and the Importance of Humidity Control&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bambu Lab Automatic Material System (AMS) revolutionizes 3D printing by
streamlining filament management for multi-material and multi-color projects.
Designed to work seamlessly with Bambu Lab’s advanced 3D printers, the AMS
automates filament swapping and ensures precise material handling, eliminating
manual intervention during complex prints. With its smart storage and
compatibility with various filament types, it enhances productivity and reduces
the risk of errors, making it an essential tool for professionals and hobbyists
alike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A feature of the AMS is its focus on humidity control, a critical factor in
maintaining filament quality. It does this by utilizing an air-tight seal and
with the help of dessicant material, it absorbs moisture to keep the moisture
away from filament.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Humidity Sensor also detects the humidity inside the AMS and provides
information to the user when the humidity is higher or the dessicant may need to
be replaced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/3d-printing/ams-inside.png&quot; alt=&quot;AMS Insides&quot; title=&quot;AMS Insides&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;why-minimize-humidity&quot;&gt;Why Minimize Humidity?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Humidity can wreak havoc on filament properties. When filaments absorb moisture,
several issues can arise during printing. Moisture-laden filaments can lead to
poor adhesion between layers, causing warping or misshaping of the final print.
Additionally, when moisture in the filament is heated during the printing
process, it turns into steam, creating tiny bubbles or voids in the extruded
material, which severely affects the strength and aesthetics of the print.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-science-behind-humidity-impact&quot;&gt;The Science Behind Humidity Impact&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At a microscopic level, moisture impacts the filament’s viscosity during the
melting process. This alteration can lead to inconsistent extrusion rates, which
are critical for precision in 3D printing. Filaments like PLA, PETG, and especially
hygroscopic materials like Nylon or TPU can absorb moisture from the air,
leading to compromised prints, such as stringing, bubbling, or weak layer
adhesion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;improvements&quot;&gt;Improvements&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the AMS system performs well in maintaining a consistent and steady
humidity level, there is still room for improvement to optimize its performance.
While it effectively handles standard conditions, certain scenarios or
environmental factors may expose limitations in its ability to maintain ideal
humidity levels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most significant issues I’ve noticed is that the desiccant used (and
sold by Bambu) isn’t rechargeable. To be frank, it’s not particularly effective
either. Each AMS unit relies on two desiccant packs, which, in my experience,
only last about a month—even in a relatively dry environment. And did I mention
they’re not rechargeable? This is because the desiccant is made from calcium
chloride (&lt;strong&gt;CaCl&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;), which inherently lacks the ability to be
regenerated for repeated use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Calcium chloride is an inorganic compound – a salt with the chemical formula
CaCl&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;. It is white flakes or pellets at room temperature, and is highly
soluble in water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enter &lt;a href=&quot;https://makerworld.com/en/models/158496#profileId-173988&quot;&gt;AMS DryPods&lt;/a&gt;
designed by &lt;a href=&quot;https://makerworld.com/en/@mcmaven&quot;&gt;mcmaven&lt;/a&gt;. With over 28k
downloads it’s one of the best solutions out there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are DryPods you might be asking? DryPods are compact desiccant packs
designed to absorb moisture and reduce humidity in enclosed spaces. DryPods
typically contain a hygroscopic material, such as silica gel or calcium
chloride, which attracts and traps moisture from the air. Depending on their
design, some DryPods are reusable and can be recharged by heating to expel
absorbed moisture, while others are single-use and need replacement after
becoming saturated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These DryPods are 3d printable and contain printable desiccant trays as well as
desiccant containers that slide inbetween the first stage feeder motors. The
containers come in several variations to include Wide DryPod options that can
hold hygrometers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For Bambu or compatible Round Hygrometer with vertical or 30 degree tabs,
with a hole all the way through it, which should generate more accurate
measurements. A 42mm diameter x 14mm deep body and a 46mm diameter bezel is
supported. (Default on Plate 1.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For Bambu or compatible Round Hygrometer with a shallow hole for the
hygrometer, which allows the DryPod hold more desiccant, but may be less
accurate in measuring the overall humidity level of the AMS. A 42mm diameter x
14mm deep body and a 46mm diameter bezel is supported. (Floating).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For the Bambu Rectangular Hygrometer.  A 45x26x15mm body and a 48x29mm bezel
is supported. (Floating).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For the Xiaomi Bluetooth Thermometer Hygrometer. A 43x43x12.5 mm body is
supported.(Floating).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The integration of a hygrometer in the AMS DryPods setup allows for real-time
monitoring of the humidity levels. This precision ensures that the environment
within the DryPod remains at an ideal humidity level, often recommended to be
below 15% for most materials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are also smaller containers (narrower) that can be slotted on the outside
of the feeder motors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With fresh desiccant, the humidity dropped to 10% (Level 1) within a few hours
and remained as low as 20% (Level 2) even after six months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stefan from CNC Kitchen has created an excellent and detailed video exploring
the different types of desiccants, their pros and cons, and various methods for
drying them. While he focuses heavily on filament bags, the drying techniques he
explains are equally applicable to loose desiccant. It’s an insightful resource
for anyone looking to optimize moisture control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/6tHInlFfMcM?si=GHvj8z9lFUF0ORSI&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The integration of systems like the Bambu Lab AMS with advanced humidity
controls such as DryPods using rechargeable desiccant highlights the growing
sophistication of 3D printing technology. By tackling the critical issue of
humidity’s impact on filaments, Bambu Lab is setting a new standard for
reliability and efficiency in 3D printing. These innovations empower both
enthusiasts and professionals to achieve higher-quality results with greater
consistency. As the industry continues to evolve, systems like these are likely
to become essential tools in the world of additive manufacturing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;stuff-i-use&quot;&gt;Stuff I use&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07GR67G1M/?th=1&quot;&gt;Hygrometer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B013L31PQ0/?th=1&quot;&gt;Dry &amp;amp; Dry Silica Beads&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 03:56:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025/01/24/AMS-dry-pods/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025/01/24/AMS-dry-pods/</guid>
        
        <category>3d printing</category>
        
        <category>bambu</category>
        
        <category>makers</category>
        
        <category>3d-Printing</category>
        
        <category>ams</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fitness Goals</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;a-year-in-review-my-2024-fitness-journey-and-goals-for-2025&quot;&gt;A Year in Review: My 2024 Fitness Journey and Goals for 2025&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2024 has been a transformative year for my fitness journey. Embracing a
healthier lifestyle, I managed to shed an incredible 34 pounds—a milestone that
has significantly improved both my physical health and mental well-being. This
achievement was fueled by a combination of disciplined eating habits, regular
exercise routines, and an unwavering commitment to my goals. Reflecting on this
journey, I’m not just proud of the weight I’ve lost but also the strength and
endurance I’ve gained.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/weight-loss.png&quot; alt=&quot;Weight Loss Chart&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we step into 2025, I’m eager to build on this foundation with new challenges
and ambitions. My goal for this year is to lose an additional 20 pounds. This
target is not just about reducing the number on the scale but also about
refining and optimizing my diet and fitness regimen to maintain sustainable
health benefits. I plan to incorporate more plant-based meals into my diet and
increase my daily physical activity by introducing more consistent cardio
sessions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, 2025 will be the year I venture into weight lifting. I aim to develop
a structured strength training program that will not only aid in weight loss but
also build muscle mass and enhance overall body composition. This new focus on
lifting weights will be crucial for improving my bone density, boosting
metabolism, and increasing muscle strength—all essential components of a
holistic approach to health and fitness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Embarking on this dual journey of weight loss and strength training is both
exciting and daunting. However, the success of the past year provides a solid
blueprint for what dedication and perseverance can achieve. I look forward to
sharing my experiences, the challenges I face, and the milestones I reach.
Here’s to a healthier, stronger 2025!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 10:10:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025/01/02/fitness-goals/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025/01/02/fitness-goals/</guid>
        
        <category>2025 Goals</category>
        
        <category>2024 Review</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Reading Goals</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;surpassing-goals-and-setting-new-horizons-my-reading-journey-from-2024-to-2025&quot;&gt;Surpassing Goals and Setting New Horizons: My Reading Journey from 2024 to 2025&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we welcome the new year, it’s a perfect time to reflect on our
accomplishments and set new targets. In 2024, I set a modest goal for myself to
read 16 books. Reading has always been a way for me to unwind and learn, but
last year, it became more than just a hobby—it became a journey of discovery and
achievement. To my own surprise, I didn’t just meet my goal; I soared past it,
finishing 23 books and covering a whopping 8,037 pages!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This experience was illuminating in several ways. Not only did it reaffirm my
love for reading, but it also pushed me to explore genres and authors I might
not have considered before. The books ranged from technical tomes that enhanced
my professional skills to imaginative works of fiction that transported me to
different worlds. Each page turned added a new layer to my understanding and
appreciation of the written word, making the year both enriching and
intellectually satisfying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspired by last year’s success, I’ve decided to ambitiously set my 2025 reading
goal at 30 books. This new target is not just about quantity, but also about
continuing to diversify the types of books I engage with. I plan to delve deeper
into non-fiction, exploring topics in history and science, while still enjoying
the fictional realms of fantasy and mystery that I love so much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reaching this goal will undoubtedly require discipline and dedication,
especially with a busy schedule. However, the joy and knowledge gained from each
book make every minute spent reading worthwhile. I’m excited about the
challenges and discoveries that lie ahead in my 2025 reading adventure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those looking to embark on their own reading journey, or anyone seeking to
surpass their previous achievements, let’s remind ourselves that goals are not
just endpoints but stepping stones to greater achievements. Here’s to a year
filled with wonderful reads and inspiring stories!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 08:56:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025/01/01/reading-goals/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025/01/01/reading-goals/</guid>
        
        <category>2025 Goals</category>
        
        <category>2024 Review</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wishful Thinking</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;wishful-thinking&quot;&gt;Wishful Thinking&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wishful thinking is the act of believing or hoping for something to be true,
often without regard to logic, evidence, or practicality. It involves imagining
a desired outcome, even if it’s unrealistic or unlikely, because it aligns with
personal desires or fantasies. This type of thinking can lead people to make
decisions based on what they want to happen rather than what is actually
probable or reasonable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, someone might hope for a promotion at work despite a lack of
qualifications, just because they want it to happen. Or someone might ignore
signs of an unhealthy relationship, believing it will improve on its own because
they deeply wish it will. While wishful thinking can offer comfort, it can also
lead to disappointment if it disconnects from reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or as my grandfather used to say&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Wish in one hand, shit in the other, see which one fills up first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 09:37:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024/12/24/wishful-thinking/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024/12/24/wishful-thinking/</guid>
        
        <category>philosophy</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Gaming History - Part 1</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Image Credits:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.shutterstock.com/gallery-891097p1.html&quot;&gt;karnoff&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.shutterstock.com/&quot;&gt;Shutterstock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been gaming for what seems like forever and to be honest, compared to most
of you I have been. This is a brief history of my love affair with gaming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;the-early-days&quot;&gt;The Early Days&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1977, Atari released the Atari VCS (later known as the Atari 2600).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it was released, the Atari VCS was only designed to play 10 simple
challenge games. However, the console included an external ROM slot where game
cartridges could be plugged in; the potential was quickly discovered by
programmers around the world, who created games far outperforming the console’s
original designed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The original list of games:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Air-Sea Battle&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Basic Math&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blackjack&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Combat&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Indy 500&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Star Ship&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Street Racer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Surround&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Video Olympics&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pong&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The integration of the microprocessor also led to the release of Space Invaders
for the Atari VCS in 1980, signifying a new era of gaming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/gaming/Atari-2600.png&quot; alt=&quot;Atari 2600&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Atari 2600&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got an Atari 2600 sometime right around christmas of 1980 and grew to love the
like Asteroids, Pitfall, Frogger, Pong, Space Invaders and of course Adventure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;pc-gaming---the-start&quot;&gt;PC Gaming - The Start&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1980 I was in sixth grade and attending Lakewood Elementary School in Euless
Texas. I got accepted into their “Talented and Gifted Program” and started
taking programming classes on the TRS 80 using Level III BASIC (Beginners’
All-purpose Symbolic Instruction Code) developed by Microsoft. All our
development at that time was done using audio cassette drives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because I had been playing quite a bit of Adventure and the fact that the TRS 80
had at best rudimentary graphics I started learning how to program “Adventure”
style games on those TRS 80’s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That really was my first adventure into both programming and PC Gaming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;pc-gaming---the-next-phase&quot;&gt;PC Gaming - The Next Phase&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I continued to play around with programming computers all through High School
and then ended up in the Military for a few years. While in the military I
continued to play games mostly on a Commodore 64 System although I also played
around on the IBM XT (8088 based), the IBM Personal Computer/AT (80286 based)
and the XT 286 (also 80286 based).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I left Active Duty Military in 1991 I ended up purchasing a Intel 386 based
system which was a 32-bit microprocessor first introduced in 1985 but not really
affordable until a few years afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was at this time that he first real commercial games became available via BBS
and were considered shareware. The majority of these games came from iD Software
and included the following titles:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Commander Keen in Invasion of the Vorticons (released on December 14, 1990)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wolfenstein 3D (released on May 5, 1992)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Doom (released on December 10, 1993)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1993/1994 I got my first Intel 486 based system and moved to Silicon Valley
to begin working professionally as a Software Engineer and continued to play
video games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;pc-gaming---mmo-phase&quot;&gt;PC Gaming - MMO Phase&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I continued to play most of these games when I first moved to California and in
1997 I found Massively Multiplayer Online Games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What exactly is a Massively Multiplayer Online Game?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A massively multiplayer online game (MMOG or more commonly MMO) is an online
video game with a large numbers of players, often hundreds or thousands, on
the same server. MMOs usually feature a huge, persistent open world, although
there are games that differ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The list of MMO’s that I started playing in order are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ultima Online (released on September 24, 1997)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Everquest (released on March 16, 1999)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Asheron’s Call (released on November 2, 1999)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Anarchy Online (released on June 27, 2001)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Asheron’s Call 2 (released on November 22, 2002)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eve Online (released on May 6, 2003)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;World of Worldcraft (released on November 23, 2004)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was working in Silicon Valley for a few years, and at this point, I had
co-founded the Open Source web site &lt;a href=&quot;http://sf.net&quot;&gt;SourceForge&lt;/a&gt; and then got laid
off from VA Software. At the time I got laid off I received a really good
package and was spending a lot of my time mostly playing Asheron’s Call and
Anarchy Online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a matter of fact, I had stayed up all night playing both of those games when
the first events of September 11th 2001 occurred.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few months after the events of 9/11 I ended up started a game development
studio called Damage Studios.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Located in San Francisco, California, Damage Studios is developing
Rekonstruction as a persistent online title where a futuristic Earth must be
rebuilt following a devastating asteroid collision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;to-be-continued&quot;&gt;To be continued&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well that’s the end of Part -1. I will be continuing the story about Damage
Studios and Rekonstruction in a future post (Part 2) and then conclude my gaming
journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;thanks for reading.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:20:53 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024/08/30/my-gaming-history-part-1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024/08/30/my-gaming-history-part-1/</guid>
        
        <category>gaming</category>
        
        <category>games</category>
        
        <category>pc</category>
        
        <category>console</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New Job, New Location</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;exiting-apple&quot;&gt;Exiting Apple&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working at Apple is often seen as the pinnacle of success in the tech industry—a
place where innovation thrives and the brightest minds collaborate to create
world-changing products. However, beneath the surface of this high-performance
environment lies a culture that can be toxic and stifling, marked by intense
micromanagement and an overwhelming pressure to perform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The demand for perfection at Apple is relentless. While this has led to some of
the most iconic products in the world, it also creates an atmosphere where
employees often feel they are constantly walking on eggshells. Decisions are
scrutinized at every level, and the need for approval from multiple layers of
management can slow down even the simplest of tasks. This culture of
micromanagement not only hinders creativity but also breeds a sense of distrust,
where employees may hesitate to take initiative or think outside the box for
fear of being second-guessed or reprimanded.\&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Toxicity in this environment often stems from the intense pressure to deliver
results, which can lead to a work culture that values output over well-being.
The expectation to be “always on” creates a cycle of burnout that is difficult
to break. Employees may find themselves working long hours, sacrificing personal
time, and constantly pushing beyond their limits, all while receiving little
recognition or support. This not only affects morale but also takes a toll on
mental health, creating an unsustainable work-life balance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite these challenges, the experience at Apple is a double-edged sword. The
brand’s prestige and the opportunity to work on groundbreaking projects are
undeniable draws. However, it’s essential to acknowledge the less glamorous side
of the company culture—a side that can be draining and demoralizing, even for
the most passionate and dedicated professionals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having said all that, after almost 4 years at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;the spaceship&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and working
with some amazing people (some not &lt;em&gt;ALL&lt;/em&gt;), I made decision back in October to
leave Apple and look for someting else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;new-beginnings&quot;&gt;New Beginnings&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ended up taking a position at the first company I interviewed with. Most of
the reasons are listed below but what isn’t mentioned below was the opportunity
to work with some other ex-Apple folks that I respected a great deal as well as
the job being full remote. Not some bullshit RTO Mandate that involved
commuting to Apple Park to manage a team that wasn’t in fact local.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joining GEICO as the Senior Director of Engineering for Hybrid Cloud SRE is an
exciting new chapter in my career, one that comes at a pivotal moment for the
company. GEICO is undergoing a significant transformation, shifting from a
traditional IT organization to a forward-thinking Engineering organization. This
transition is more than just a change in titles or processes—it’s a fundamental
reimagining of how we approach technology, problem-solving, and innovation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past, IT organizations have often been seen as reactive, primarily
focused on maintaining systems and responding to issues as they arise. But as
the landscape of technology evolves, so too must our approach. At GEICO, we are
moving towards a model where engineering principles drive our decisions and
strategies. This shift means embracing a culture of continuous improvement,
automation, and resilience. It’s about empowering teams to build, innovate, and
take ownership of their work, rather than just maintaining what already exists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we transition to this new model, my role in Hybrid Cloud SRE will be crucial.
We’re focusing on building robust, scalable, and highly available cloud
environments that support our engineering teams and drive business outcomes.
This involves not just adopting new technologies, but also fostering a mindset
where reliability, automation, and proactive problem-solving are at the core of
everything we do. It’s an exciting time to be at GEICO, and I’m eager to
contribute to this transformation, helping to lead our teams into a future where
engineering excellence is the norm, not the exception.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The journey ahead will undoubtedly come with its challenges, but it’s these
challenges that make the transformation so rewarding. I’m looking forward to
collaborating with talented professionals across the company, leveraging our
collective expertise to build something truly remarkable. This is more than just
a job—it’s an opportunity to be part of a movement that will redefine how GEICO
approaches technology and engineering in the years to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;one-more-thing&quot;&gt;One More Thing&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To quote Steve Jobs….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So since the GEICO position was full remote and since we were looking for a
place to retire we ended up purchasing a house in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bandera,_Texas&quot;&gt;Bandera
TX&lt;/a&gt;. While it’s a pretty small
town (under 900 people or so) and pretty remote we’re still only 25 minutes away
from Boerne and 40 minutes away from San Antonio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bonus is we were able to get a house with a huge workshop for me and my
projects and the local electric co-operative also provided a 2gig fiber link to
the house (take that Silicon Valley). While we’re not selling the house in Half
Moon Bay anytime soon we are splitting time between the two houses (mostly
Nicole and Patrick in CA).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well thanks for taking the time to read and here’s some gratuitious photos:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://photos.app.goo.gl/fg9o4nVQQsK5Tk6d9&quot;&gt;Bandera House Photos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 16:37:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024/08/23/new-job-new-location/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024/08/23/new-job-new-location/</guid>
        
        <category>New Job</category>
        
        <category>New House</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I&apos;m back</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Returning to the world of blogging after nearly four years at Apple feels like
rediscovering an old friend. The time away has been transformative, filled with
incredible experiences, challenges, and growth. But as fulfilling as my work at
Apple was, it came with certain limitations—most notably, the company’s strict
policies regarding personal expression online. Blogging, a platform I once
freely embraced to share thoughts, ideas, and experiences, had to take a
backseat due to these draconian rules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple’s approach to employee communication is well-known for its rigor. The
company prioritizes confidentiality and control over its narrative, which means
that employees are often restricted from sharing their work or opinions
publicly. For someone who thrives on writing and sharing insights, this was a
tough adjustment. The rules are there for good reasons, protecting innovation
and maintaining a unified message, but they also stifle personal expression,
making it nearly impossible to keep up a blog without crossing lines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, as I step away from that chapter, I find myself eager to reconnect with the
blogging community. The hiatus has given me new perspectives and a deeper
understanding of technology, innovation, and the complexities of working within
such a tightly controlled environment. I’m excited to bring these insights into
my writing, blending my experiences at Apple with a renewed commitment to open
and honest dialogue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blogging again feels like a breath of fresh air—a chance to engage with ideas
and conversations that were put on hold. I look forward to sharing more in the
coming weeks and months, exploring new topics, and reconnecting with readers
who, like me, value the freedom to express themselves openly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, more posts coming in the next few weeks talking about what I’m doing
next and where that’s happening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 07:20:53 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024/08/23/im-back/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024/08/23/im-back/</guid>
        
        <category>Blogging</category>
        
        <category>Apple</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Return to 3d Printing</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been thinking about picking up some new 3d printers for awhile now as my
&lt;a href=&quot;http://fusion94.org/2015/09/10/flashforge-creator-pro/&quot;&gt;FlashForge Creator
Pros&lt;/a&gt; are starting to
show their age and one just doesn’t print at all anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting new printers (other than having a up-to-date platform) serves a few
purposes for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For one, Patrick is getting to the age (10) where he’s spending a lot of time on
his smartphone and in games. I hope to use 3d Printing to teach him new skills,
empower his creativity, make family memories, and teach him a world of science
and design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I did a little bit of research and decided to go with a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.creality.com/products/creality-ender-3-s1-pro-fdm-3d-printer&quot;&gt;Creality Ender 3 S1
Pro&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;enter-creality&quot;&gt;Enter Creality&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, it’s been a great printer with regards to ease of unboxing/installation
as well as the overall quality of the prints w/o any tuning whatsoever. It was
truly the easiest printer I’ve ever assembled. IIRC it was literally 11 bolts.
Dead Simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;some-of-the-key-features-are&quot;&gt;Some of the key features are:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Print size: 220 x 220 x 270 mm&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Up to 300°C high-temp printing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Full-metal dual-gear direct extruder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CR-touch automatic leveling&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4.3″ display&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Easy to assemble&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With regards to setup and tuning? Straight out of the box it’s an amazing
printer. Here are a couple of shots of it as well as some of the initial prints:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/3d-printing/creality-ender-3.jpg&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/3d-printing/ce3-print-1.jpg&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/3d-printing/ce3-print-2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/3d-printing/ce3-print-3.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Gallery / Creality&lt;/em&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having said that, after doing some additional research I ended up reading a ton
of reviews and watching many, many YouTube videos about the Bambu X1-Carbon. Due
to some of these reviews I bit the bullet and pulled the trigger on one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;enter-bambu&quot;&gt;Enter Bambu&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I purchased a &lt;a href=&quot;https://store.bambulab.com/products/x1-carbon-combo&quot;&gt;Bambu X1-Carbon
Combo&lt;/a&gt; on 7/17/2023 and it
arrived via UPS on 7/20/2023. It sat in it’s box for a few days until I could
find time for the assembly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The printer is shipped in a pretty large cardboard box, with foam protection on
the sides. The printer is packed well so I didn’t expect any kind of damage
during shipping. It can be easily taken out from the package by simply pulling
from the sides of the plastic bag (But do take care here as plastic bags have a
tendency to rip and tear).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the printer comes pre-assembled (mostly); before you can start printing
you will need to remove a few screws that hold some parts in place during
shipping. If you purchased the AMS unit you will also need to remove it from the
printer’s enclosure via a few additional screws.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will also need to attach the touchscreen to the printer via a supplied
ribbon cable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall the assembly process took longer than the Creality Ender 3 S1 Pro but
will still under an hour and signficantly easier that other printers that I’ve
owned in the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;some-of-the-key-features-and-improvements&quot;&gt;Some of the Key features and improvements:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Large 256mm x 256mm x 256mm Build Volume&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Compatible Printing Materials Up to 300°C&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Built-In Camera Monitoring&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Compatible with Abrasive Filaments (NylonX, NylonG, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Capable of Multi-Color and Multi-Material 3D Printing
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Up to 16 colors printing&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;High quality printing with 7 μm Lidar Resolution&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;High speed CoreXY with 20000 mm/s² Acceleration&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dual Auto Bed Leveling&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;AI inspected first layer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spaghetti failure detection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is some feedback and a few thoughts after owning the Bambu for a few
months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;1-its-very-fast&quot;&gt;1) It’s very fast.&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Very very fast. I did a large sample print as a reference
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.printables.com/model/152592-honeycomb-storage-wall/files#preview:file-QLLx0&quot;&gt;wall-honeycomb-part.stl&lt;/a&gt;
and the Bambu was approximately 240.63% faster than the Creality Ender 3 S1
Pro.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Printer&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Total Time&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;Time in Minutes&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Bambu&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;1h 36m&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;96&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Creality&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;5h 27m&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;327&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;2-its-slow&quot;&gt;2) It’s slow.&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By this I mean it’s not slow at printing it’s slow at getting ready to print. On
average about 7.3% of the total print time is in setup or prep. i.e. homing the
bed and leveling, checking resonance, calibrating input shaping and pressure
advance for extrusion. This also doesn’t account for bed and nozzle heating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;3-extruderhot-end-swap&quot;&gt;3) Extruder/Hot End swap&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Changing the hotend/extruder on the Creality is as simple as grabbing a wrench,
untightening the exiting nozzle and tightening the new nozzle. As Bambu uses a
completely integrated hotend/extruder it’s slightly more complicated. Here’s how
that works:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;removal&quot;&gt;Removal&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Go to the Temperature/Axis settings and make sure your hotend temperature is
at 30c or below, then turn the power OFF&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Open the magnetic cover and move it aside&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gently remove the bigger 2-pin plug of the ceramic heater, the 4-pin plug of
the cooling fan and the very small 2-pin plug of the thermistor&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use the H2 Allen key to unscrew the 2 screws that are near the top of the
nozzles’ heatsink&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Carefully and gently move the wires out of the plastic wire clip and remove
the complete hotend assembly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;installation&quot;&gt;Installation&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Position the complete hotend assembly so that the 2 screw holes will be
behind the bracket&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gently push the 2 screws in and then tighten them equally (but careful not to
overtighten)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Plug in the bigger 2-pin ceramic heater plug, the 4-pin cooling fan plug, and
the very small 2-pin thermistor plug&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Route all the loose cables through the plastic wire clip&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Replace the magnetic cover… and you are done!!!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I said, slightly more complicated but not completely horrible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;4-build-plates&quot;&gt;4) Build Plates&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default the Bambu X1-C comes with both the Bambu Cool Plate and a Bambu
Engineering Plate which is going to require the use of a glue stick or painter’s
tape to ensure great adhesion. The Creality Ender 3 S1 Pro by default came with
a spring steel textured PEI plate which is far superior. If you chose to pick up
a Bambu X1-C then you should (at the time of purchase) add on a &lt;a href=&quot;https://us.store.bambulab.com/products/bambu-textured-pei-plate&quot;&gt;Bambu Textured
PEI Plate&lt;/a&gt; as
well. Trust me it’s worth the $37.99 USD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;5-filaments&quot;&gt;5) Filaments&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bambu X1-C comes with some starter filament. One of the things I love about
the AMS unit is the ability to read and register filament via RFID.
Unfortunately this is only available through the use of Bambu Filaments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially the price of Bambu filaments versus say Polymaker there appears to be
a $3 to $4 difference per kg. While this might be a problem for some I’ve not
found it to be a showstopper due to the aforementioned RFID tagging for
filament.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few other things to note is that once you have a few empty spools or order the
empty spools from Bambu for the most part you should be ordered filament via the
refill option which brings the prices inline with Polymaker. The process of
refilling a spool takes 3-4 minutes and requires no tools or winders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Filament orders can only happen through the Bambu Store, there is no Amazon
option (booooooo) and shipping options (via FedEx) can take up to 10 days so
plan accordingly. I think my second filament order was in the neighborhood of
30kgs and somewhere around $750 USD but I didn’t have to order filament for a
few more months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;final-thoughts&quot;&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I liked my original Bambu X1-C so much that I ending up purchasing a second unit
as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I earnestly believe that the Bambu X1-C printer delivers commercial quality at a
consumer price point and it’s well worth the cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a photo gallery of some of the prints from the Bambu X1-C:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/3d-printing/bambu-1.JPG&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/3d-printing/bambu-2.JPG&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/3d-printing/bambu-3.JPG&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/3d-printing/bambu-4.JPG&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/3d-printing/bambu-5.JPG&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/3d-printing/bambu-6.JPG&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/3d-printing/bambu-7.JPG&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/3d-printing/bambu-8.JPG&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/3d-printing/bambu-9.JPG&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/3d-printing/bambu-10.JPG&quot; /&gt;    
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Gallery / Bambu X1-C Prints&lt;/em&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can certainly state the experience now days is significantly better than when
I put my first 3D Printer together, a Prusa Mendel that is show below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/3d-printing/prusa-mendel.png&quot; alt=&quot;Prusa Mendel&quot; title=&quot;Prusa Mendel&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For reference that mendel was put together in 2011 and the printable parts were
printed using a Makerbot Cupcake CNC from 2009.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now for some gratuitous photos of that Cupcake CNC&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/3d-printing/cupcake-1.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/3d-printing/cupcake-2.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/3d-printing/cupcake-3.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/3d-printing/cupcake-4.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/3d-printing/cupcake-5.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Gallery / Makerbot Cupcake CNC&lt;/em&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 13:20:53 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/09/13/return-3d-printing/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/09/13/return-3d-printing/</guid>
        
        <category>3d printing</category>
        
        <category>bambu</category>
        
        <category>makers</category>
        
        <category>3d-Printing</category>
        
        <category>printables</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dual Universe Release</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Dual Universe is a first person based space simulation sandbox massively
multiplayer online role play game (MMORPG) video game in development by the
Paris-based game development studio, Novaquark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the last few years I’ve sunk an enormous amount of time playing
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dualuniverse.game/&quot;&gt;Dual Universe&lt;/a&gt;. Which for the most part I’ve
thoroughly enjoyed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It basically combined elements of games I’ve played for years now,
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eveonline.com/&quot;&gt;Eve Online&lt;/a&gt; (released in 2003) and
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nomanssky.com/&quot;&gt;No Man’s Sky&lt;/a&gt; (released in 2016). It also
incorporates bits and pieces from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.minecraft.net/&quot;&gt;Minecraft&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going through my email I was able to locate this one from August, 28th, 2019 or
3 years ago to the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Hello Novean,&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;You recently signed up to create a Dual Universe account. To validate your
email, please click on the link below to finalize setting up your account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve spent years invested in DU and have reported bugs and exploits over that
time. I’ve spent day’s on end in mining for resources (prior to automatic mining
units) just so that I could build Space Station’s and other bases on multiple
planets. I currently have 4 characters/accounts in-game and between the 4
characters I have accumulated somewhere close to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;171m Talent Points&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1.27b Quanta (in-game currency)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game launched in May 2016 in its &lt;strong&gt;pre-alpha&lt;/strong&gt; state and entered &lt;strong&gt;Beta&lt;/strong&gt; in
August of 2020. The &lt;strong&gt;live release&lt;/strong&gt; date for Dual Universe is 27 September 2022. The question of whether Dual Universe will wipe its servers at launch is
one that has been hanging over players’ heads as far back as June when the devs
at Novaquark openly ruminated about the decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On August 9th, Novaquark &lt;a href=&quot;https://board.dualthegame.com/index.php?/topic/25065-dual-universe-reset-news-announcement/&quot;&gt;announced that yes&lt;/a&gt;, there will be a full server reset
at launch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Existing players will still retain their blueprints, friend lists, and guild
details, while everything from planets to territories to constructs will be
reset. This is being done for several reasons, including to give everyone even
footing, better balance the economy, improve performance, and add new planets as
well as adjust existing ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a &lt;strong&gt;thank-you&lt;/strong&gt; to beta testers, DU will be handing out Pioneer Packs full of
talent points, currency, and other materials in order to give players back some
of their progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PIONEER PACK - EXOTIC&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This package is available to players who have purchased at least thirteen months
of subscription for the Dual Universe beta. Please note that it’s not necessary
to have used the game time by this date to qualify for this bracket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This package is also available to our Gold backers and above from our
crowdfunding campaigns, as well as Sponsors and Patrons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Up to 52,992,000 extra talent points, including the server-wide accelerator event and the beta talent point awards, by the end of the 6-month launch event.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6 monthly payments of 400,000 quanta.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5 Schematic copies of Dynamic Core Unit S&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5 Schematic copies of Dynamic Core Unit M&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5 Schematic copies of Dynamic Core Unit L&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tier 3 Rare Item - 1 Circinus collectible statue&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 exclusive decorative items: Deco potted plant white, Deco carpet, Deco potted plant black&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The
&lt;a href=&quot;https://board.dualthegame.com/index.php?/topic/25064-reset-news-announcement-discussion-thread/&quot;&gt;response&lt;/a&gt;
to the server reset by the players has been mixed at best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be honest I’m not sure how I feel about the idea of the reset. From a game
balancing standpoint I totally understand it. They want to ensure that the new
players that will be joining for the first time on launch will not feel
disadvantaged. On the other hand, DU has been in beta for 2 years now and anyone
could have put down a credit card and started playing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way the tiered-pioneer pack is setup, my 3 years of work during the beta
means just as much as anyone that signs up today (for at least a 13 month
subscription) will get the same pioneer pack as me and yet I’ve invested
countless more hours and money into DU. That’s some &lt;strong&gt;thank-you&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To me this seems like a quick cash grab from Novaquark especially considering
the game has been in development for 8 years (bleeding money) and also that at
launch, the version launching is in many ways inferior to the version that’s
currently running as beta. Not all the planets that are currently in beta will
be launching. Some will be delayed for awhile. This will lead to some early
initial planets suffering from overcrowding and can potentially lead to whole
planets becoming like Market 6 on Alioth back in the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think what’s most likely to happen is that I will continue to invest a little
bit of time into Dual Universe after launch but uncertain as to whether or not I
will renew my subscriptions on expiration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a real shame as DU had so much potential but for whatever reason never
quite reached it. I would respect NQ a hell of a lot more if they’d just come
out and state &lt;strong&gt;“hey we’re running out of cash and need to launch with a new
influx of cash and new players to ensure we can continue to develop DU”&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead we get typical NQ marketing bullshit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 08:20:53 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2022/08/28/dual-universe/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2022/08/28/dual-universe/</guid>
        
        <category>gaming</category>
        
        <category>du</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>