<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>fusion94.org</title>
    <description>Totally Random Musings from the Edge</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2022 13:25:01 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2022 13:25:01 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>No Man's Sky</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;this is a test and only a test it’s probably broken&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 15:20:53 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2022/08/26/nms/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2022/08/26/nms/</guid>
        
        <category>gaming</category>
        
        <category>NMS</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Droning in Texas</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Federal law requires all recreational flyers to pass an aeronautical knowledge
and safety test. The FAA developed The Recreational UAS Safety Test (TRUST)
to meet this requirement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been working at a friends working ranch just outside of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kerrville,_Texas&quot;&gt;Kerrville
Texas&lt;/a&gt; since February under what
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com&quot;&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt; calls a Temporary Remote Working Arrangement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several years ago I reached out to my buddy &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCDJTTSDMIOMVrxNfssXcMrQ&quot;&gt;Michael
Rollins&lt;/a&gt; with regards
to drones as the ranch owner wanted to purchase one to perform random tasks on
the property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I met Michael way back in 2004-2005 or so playing &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldofwarcraft.com/&quot;&gt;World of
Warcraft&lt;/a&gt;. Over the years we’ve become pretty good
friends and one of his many hobbies has been flying and building drones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on Michael’s recommendation a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dji.com/phantom-4-pro-v2?site=brandsite&amp;amp;from=eol_phantom-4-pro&quot;&gt;DJI Phanton
4&lt;/a&gt;
was purchased.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;drone-tasks&quot;&gt;Drone Tasks&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the tasks that can be performed are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;surveying pastures&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;surveying fences&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;wildlife surveys&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;roof inspections&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In pasture surveying, aerial technology lets ranchers easily map plant height,
plant health, monitor weather damage as well as irrigation across their
properties, so that they can take immediate action when issues arise. This will
generally require additional 3rd party sensors and software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fencing is an area of ranching that frequently requires a lot of attention and
upkeep. Previous to drone technology, workers would survey the perimeter of the
ranch to ensure the fence was still intact. A broken fence causes issues like
allowing animals to escape, providing easy access inside to hunters, or mixing
livestock with neighbors. By using software features like Live Map, ranchers can
pinpoint the affected areas before physically arriving with their tools. Not
only does this cut down on time, but it’s also a more reliable method than
out-of-date or cloudy satellite imagery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Utilizing a drone for wildlife surveys is more accurate and consistent compared
to alternatives like manned aviation or physically walking the property. One can
fly lower than manned aviation to get higher quality images and be more
transparent than a team physically walking around the property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;drone-training-and-use&quot;&gt;Drone Training and Use&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a recreational drone pilot you need to understand some basic rules and get
certified by taking &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.faa.gov/uas/recreational_fliers/knowledge_test_updates/&quot;&gt;The Recreational UAS
Safety Test
(TRUST)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TRUST stands for The Recreational UAS Safety Test. It provides education and
testing for recreational drone flyers on important safety and regulatory
information. If you fly your drone recreationally under the Exception for
Recreational Flyers, you must pass the test before you fly. Federal law requires
all recreational flyers to pass an aeronautical knowledge and safety test. The
FAA developed The Recreational UAS Safety Test to meet this requirement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TRUST is free, can be taken online through a variety of FAA-approved test
administrators, and typically takes 30 minutes or less to complete. After you
pass the test, you will receive a completion certificate. &lt;strong&gt;Be sure to keep this
certificate with you when you fly your drone, either in paper or electronic
format.&lt;/strong&gt; Test administrators will not keep a record of your completion
certificate, therefore if you lose your certificate, you need re-take the TRUST.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The below organizations have all been approved by the FAA to administer the
TRUST as of April 2022:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trust.modelaircraft.org/&quot;&gt;Academy of Model Aeronautics (AMA)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scouting.org/the-recreational-uas-safety-test/&quot;&gt;Boy Scouts of America&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cvtc.edu/academics/certificates/aviation/faa-approved-ta-trust&quot;&gt;Chippewa Valley Technical College&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trust.turbine.us.com/&quot;&gt;Community College of Allegheny County – West Hills Center&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://my.crossflightskysolutions.com/faa-trust/&quot;&gt;CrossFlight Sky Solutions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dronelaunchacademy.com/trust/&quot;&gt;Drone Launch Academy LLC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dronetrust.com/faa-trust/&quot;&gt;Drone Trust&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://faatrust.thedroneu.com/&quot;&gt;Drone U&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://erau.edu/gaetz-aerospace-institute/faa-trust&quot;&gt;Embry-Riddle Aeronautical University (ERAU)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://aaollc.com/recreational-uas-safety-course/&quot;&gt;HSU Educational Foundation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lakeareatech.edu/connections/corporate-education/the-recreational-uas-safety-test-trust/&quot;&gt;Lake Area Technical College&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://newcollegeinstitute.org/trust/&quot;&gt;New College Institute (NCI)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trust.pilotinstitute.com/&quot;&gt;Pilot Institute&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://proctorio.com/faa/trust&quot;&gt;Proctorio Incorporated&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tacavpro.com/trust-certification/&quot;&gt;Tactical Aviation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://uavcoach.com/faa-recreational-drone-training/&quot;&gt;UAV Coach&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uagc.edu/partnerships/corporate/faa-trust&quot;&gt;University of Arizona Global Campus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.volatusaerospace.com/training/faa-trust-test-administrator/&quot;&gt;Volatus Aerospace Corp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;basic-rules&quot;&gt;Basic Rules&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;you must fly your drone within visual line of sight&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;stay below 400ft altitude&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;stay at least 5 miles away from an airport that might have a Part 107 requirement&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;flight operations during daylight hours only.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are also a few additional rules:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All drones must be registered, except those that weigh 0.55 pounds or less
(less than 250 grams) and are flown exclusively under the Exception for
Recreational Flyers.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drones registered under part 107 may be flown for recreational purposes as
well as under part 107.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drones registered under the Exception for Recreational Flyers cannot be flown
for Part 107 operations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because the DJI Phantom 4 weighs 1380 grams I needed to register the drone with
the FAA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;how-to-register&quot;&gt;How to Register&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;information-needed-to-register&quot;&gt;Information Needed to Register&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Physical address and mailing address (if different from physical address)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Email address&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Phone number&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make and model of your drone&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Specific Remote ID serial number provided by the manufacturer (if applicable)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Credit or debit card&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;registration-fees&quot;&gt;Registration Fees&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Part 107 registration costs $5 per drone and is valid for three (3) years.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Exception for Recreational Flyers registration costs $5 and is valid for
three (3) years.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once registered, drone registration cannot be transferred between types (part
107 or the Exception for Recreational Flyers).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;registration-requirements&quot;&gt;Registration Requirements&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;13 years of age or older (if the owner is less than 13 years of age, a person
13 years of age or older must register the drone)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A U.S. citizen or legal permanent resident.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For foreign operators, FAA will consider the certificate issued to be a
recognition of ownership rather than a certificate of U.S. aircraft
registration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;after-you-register&quot;&gt;After you Register&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you register your drone, you will receive an FAA registration certificate.
&lt;strong&gt;You must have your registration certificate (either a paper copy or digital
copy) in your possession when you fly. If another individual operates your
drone, they must have your drone registration certificate (either a paper or
digital copy) in their possession.&lt;/strong&gt; Federal law requires drone operators who
are required to register, to show their certificate of registration to any
Federal, State, or local law enforcement officer if asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Failure to register a drone that requires registration may result in regulatory
and criminal penalties. The FAA may assess civil penalties up to $27,500.
Criminal penalties include fines of up to $250,000 and/or imprisonment for up to
three (3) years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The FAA requires that you mark all drones with your registration number before
you fly them. Here is how to label your drone:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Must be maintained in a condition that is legible.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Must be affixed to the small unmanned aircraft by any means necessary to
ensure that it will remain affixed for the duration of each operation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Must be legibly displayed on an external surface of the small unmanned
aircraft.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion the steps you need to take to safely operate your drone and remain
within legal compliance isn’t all that hard to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;random-photos&quot;&gt;Random Photos&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a few shots that I was able to get on my first few flights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/droning-texas/125.PNG&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/droning-texas/162.PNG&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/droning-texas/234.PNG&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/droning-texas/280.PNG&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/droning-texas/406.PNG&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/droning-texas/433.PNG&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/droning-texas/436.PNG&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/droning-texas/783.PNG&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/droning-texas/881.PNG&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/droning-texas/6187530.jpg&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/droning-texas/8288145.jpg&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/droning-texas/8648682.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Gallery / Droning&lt;/em&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here’s a video that Michael shot around my house and the in the HMB area
about 5 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/nE2ScEx9K6U&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 00:20:53 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2022/05/07/droning/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2022/05/07/droning/</guid>
        
        <category>drones</category>
        
        <category>dji</category>
        
        <category>Texas</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I'm Back....</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m back….I promise to update more often than every 2 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Built with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Visual Studio Code&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Norlin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jekyll&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Firebase&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yeah, it’s overkill. ¯(ツ)/¯&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 14:20:53 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2022/05/05/welcome-the-hell-back/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2022/05/05/welcome-the-hell-back/</guid>
        
        <category>blogging</category>
        
        <category>website</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Living in Mountain Lion Country</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The problem for bike riders, joggers and hikers in the wilderness is that the
mountain lion has its own habitat.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Pat McDonnell&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this security camera footage was captured earlier this week approximately a
1/2 mile from my house. As such I thought it was time to write a post in regards
to Mountain Lions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;/assets/videos/mountain-lion.mp4&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;california-mountain-lions&quot;&gt;California Mountain Lions&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More than half of California is mountain lion habitat. Mountain lions generally
exist wherever deer are found. They are solitary and elusive, and their nature
is to avoid humans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mountain lions primarily eat deer, but, if allowed, they will prey on vulnerable
pets and livestock. In extremely rare cases, even people have fallen prey to
mountain lions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mountain lions that threaten people are immediately killed. Those that prey on
pets or livestock can be killed by a property owner after the required permit is
secured. Moving problem mountain lions is not an option. It causes deadly
territorial conflicts with other mountain lions already there. Or the relocated
mountain lion returns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;living-in-mountain-lion-country&quot;&gt;Living in Mountain Lion Country&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Acknowledge that you live in mountain lion country and make a commitment to
educate yourself. Talk to your neighbors and work together.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Never feed deer or other wildlife; it is illegal to feed deer and other big
game in California and it will attract mountain lions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Deer-proof your landscaping by avoiding plants that deer like to eat.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Trim brush to reduce hiding places for mountain lions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t leave small children or pets outside unattended.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Install motion-sensitive lighting around the house.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provide sturdy, covered shelters for sheep, goats, and other vulnerable
animals.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t allow pets outside when mountain lions are most active—dawn, dusk, and
at night.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bring pet food inside to avoid attracting raccoons, opossums and other
potential mountain lion prey.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;what-to-do-if-you-encounter-a-mountain-lion&quot;&gt;What to do if you Encounter a Mountain Lion&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mountain lions are quiet, solitary and elusive, and typically avoid people by
nature. However, as human population expands into mountain lion habitat, more
frequent sightings may occur and human/mountain lion encounters may increase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mountain lion attacks on humans are extremely rare. However, attacks have
occurred in California. Understanding mountain lion behavior and how to act
responsibly in mountain lion country may greatly reduce potential conflict with
these majestic animals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following safety information is a compilation taken from wildlife managers,
wildlife officers and scientists that study mountain lion behavior. Although no
strategy in the event of an encounter is guaranteed to be successful in every
situation, these tips will help keep you safe in lion country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do not hike, bike, or jog alone. Stay alert on trails.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Avoid hiking or jogging when mountain lions are most active – dawn, dusk, and
at night.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keep a close watch on small children.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Off leash dogs on trails are at increased risk of becoming prey for a
mountain lion.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Never approach a mountain lion. Give them an escape route.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;DO NOT RUN. Stay calm. Running may trigger chase, catch and kill response. Do
not turn your back. Face the animal, make noise and try to look bigger by
waving your arms, or opening your jacket if wearing one; throw rocks or other
objects. Pick up small children.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do not crouch down or bend over. Squatting puts you in a vulnerable position
of appearing much like a 4-legged prey animal.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be vocal; however, speak calmly and do not use high pitched tones or high
pitch screams.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Teach others how to behave during an encounter. Anyone who runs may initiate
an attack.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Carry and know how to use bear spray to deter a mountain lion. Bear spray has
been shown to be successful in emergency situations with mountain lions. Have
the spray readily accessible. Carry in a holster belt or attach to a mountain
bike. Talk to the folks at your local outdoor store. Make sure you know how to
properly use bear spray. People have been known to spray their own faces when
attempting to use it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If a lion attacks, fight back. Research on mountain lion attacks suggests that
many potential victims have fought back successfully with rocks, sticks,
garden tools, even an ink pen or bare hands. Try to stay on your feet. If
knocked down, try to protect head and neck.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If a mountain lion attacks a person, immediately call 911.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Report unusual mountain lion behavior to your local CDFW regional office.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 11:25:53 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/04/09/living-in-mountain-lion-country/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/04/09/living-in-mountain-lion-country/</guid>
        
        <category>cougars</category>
        
        <category>puma</category>
        
        <category>lions</category>
        
        <category>california</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>RMEF Membership Giveaway</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In a civilized and cultivated country wild animals only continue to exist at
all when preserved by sportsmen. the excellent people who protest against all
hunting, and consider sportsmen as enemies of wild life, are ignorant of the
fact that in reality the genuine sportsman is by all odds the most important
factor in keeping the larger and more valuable wild creatures from total
extermination.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Theodore Roosevelt President of the United States (#26)&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this I promise to never spam you or sell your email address. The only reason
the address is collected is to notify you of winning. Once the contest is over
the data collected on all users will be deleted.latest blog post regarding
conservation I’d like to talk to you about the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rmef.org&quot;&gt;Rocky Mountain Elk
Foundation&lt;/a&gt;, their history, what they do and how they do
it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mission of the Rocky Mountain Elk Foundation is to ensure the future of elk
other wildlife, their habitat and our hunting heritage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In support of their mission, the RMEF is committed to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;conserving, restoring and enhancing natural habitats&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;promoting the sound management of wild elk, which may be hunted or otherwise
enjoyed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;restoring elk to their native ranges&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;educating members and the public about habitat conservation and our hunting
heritage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;rmef-history&quot;&gt;RMEF History&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/rmef-founders.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; title=&quot;RMEF Founders&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;captions&quot;&gt;
Rocky Mountain Elk Foundation founders, left to right: Bob Munson, Dan Bull, Bill Munson and Charlie Decker
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1984, four hunters from Northwest Montana recognized a handful of
organizations doing great work for species like ducks, turkeys and upland birds.
They also recognized there was no group dedicated to North America’s grandest
big game animal, elk. In May of that year, they pooled their time, talent and
resources and created the Rocky Mountain Elk Foundation, an organization
dedicated to elk, elk hunting and the habitat they need to thrive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;hard-work-pays-off&quot;&gt;Hard Work Pays Off&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They set up shop in the back room of a trailer house in Troy, the four; a
pastor,a realtor, a logger and a drive-in owner, created an organization that
would directly benefit elk and other wildlife by putting money to work on the
ground. The team drained their bank accounts and borrowed funds to mail out
43,000 brochures soliciting members, promising a subscription to a magazine
about elk and elk hunting, as well as an annual international convention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They received a dismal 233 responses. But they believed they’d made a commitment
to these people. So they borrowed additional funds and printed 32,000 copies of
the premier issue of Bugle magazine, which they mailed out and time, hard work
and patience, but by the end of 1984, membership had grown to almost 2,500.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;the-first-of-many-successes-to-come&quot;&gt;The First of Many Successes to Come&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In April 1985, the Rocky Mountain Elk Foundation held their first convention in
Spokane, Washington. They also funded their first habitat project that year, a
grant to help fund a prescribed burn in a place fittingly named Elk Creek on the
Kootenai National Forest near Libby, Montana. In 1988, they facilitated their
first land acquisition, the 16,440-acre Robb Creek property in Montana, and
received their first ringing endorsement from the corporate community. At their
annual convention that year, Ray Goff, former RMEF board member and Vice
President of Anheuser-Busch, announced a $500,000 gift from the company. That
gift helped kick off their incredible growth and conservation achievements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;bursting-at-the-seams&quot;&gt;Bursting at the Seams&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By 1988, the RMEF staff had grown to 12, and their offices were spread across a
vacant dentist’s office, a mini mall and an abandoned grocery store. They now
had 32,000 members, 2,000 passionate volunteers and 70 chapters, and they had
protected and enhanced more than 110,000 acres of elk country. Bursting at the
seams, it was time to say goodbye to the RMEF’s birthplace and move to Missoula,
Montana.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;a-shining-star&quot;&gt;A Shining Star&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since then, they’ve grown to more than 227,000 members whose support has
protected and enhanced more than 7.3 million acres of North American wildlife
habitat. Hundreds of thousands of these acres were completely off-limits to the
public. They are now open for all to hunt, fish and otherwise enjoy. They employ
more than 120 people and boast more than 11,000 volunteers working through more
than 500 chapters across the United States.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the most humble beginnings in 1984, the RMEF has risen to become one of the
most effective and efficient conservation organizations in the United States.
Today, working together with members, volunteers, and partners as Team Elk, the
RMEF is striving to conserve the next million acres of elk country, and to be a
strong voice for hunters, access, and wildlife management and conservation
issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;how-they-conserve&quot;&gt;How They Conserve&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;land-protection&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#land-protection-programs&quot;&gt;Land Protection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The RMEF permanently protects crucial elk winter and summer ranges, migration
corridors, calving grounds and other vital areas, while focusing on securing and
improving hunter access throughout elk country. Their land conservation tools
include: acquisitions, access agreements and easements, conservation easements,
land and real estate donations, land exchanges and associated acres.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;habitat-stewardship&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#habitat-stewardship-programs&quot;&gt;Habitat Stewardship&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Healthy habitat is essential for healthy elk and other wildlife. The RMEF helps
fund and conduct a variety of projects to improve essential forage, water, cover
and space components of wildlife habitat, and supports research and management
efforts to help maintain productive elk herds and habitat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;elk-restoration&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#elk-restoration-programs&quot;&gt;Elk Restoration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The RMEF works to reestablish elk herds in historic ranges where the habitat and
human cultural tolerance create a high potential for self-sustaining herds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;land-protection-programs&quot;&gt;Land Protection Programs&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since 1984, the Rocky Mountain Elk Foundation has permanently protected more
than 1,700 square miles of prime habitat for elk and other wildlife across the
country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The RMEF uses advanced habitat mapping technology (GIS) to identify and
prioritize the most crucial elk winter and summer ranges, migration corridors
and calving areas. They then work with their partners, including willing
landowners, government agencies, corporations, foundations and other
conservation groups to permanently protect the most critical habitat and target
areas for public access. Their land conservation tools include: &lt;strong&gt;land
acquisitions, conservation easements, access agreements and easements, land and
real estate donations, contributions, land exchanges and associated acres.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their goals are to permanently protect the most critical elk habitat and to
increase public access opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;land-acquisitions&quot;&gt;Land Acquisitions&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The RMEF purchases key elk habitat to protect wildlife values. In most cases,
they do not retain ownership. Most often, they convey it to a federal or state
management agency (state wildlife department, U.S. Forest Service, Bureau of
Land Management, etc.). The agency then acts as a steward of the land,
protecting and enhancing wildlife habitat, while providing the public increased
recreational opportunities, including hunting and fishing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;conservation-easements&quot;&gt;Conservation Easements&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A conservation easement protects wildlife habitat on private property. It is a
voluntary legal agreement with a landowner to protect their land in perpetuity
from development and other uses that could diminish its wildlife habitat values
but still allows for many traditional uses of the land. The land remains in
private ownership and in many instances the landowner may qualify for tax
benefits. Although it is not required, the RMEF encourages landowners to allow
public access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;land-and-real-estate-donations&quot;&gt;Land and Real Estate Donations&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Donating land for conservation purposes is one of the finest legacies a person
can leave to future generations. The RMEF may accept donations of land or real
estate from private individuals or corporations. Depending on the type of real
estate, they may retain ownership, convey the property to a private citizen
(after protecting it with a conservation easement), state, or federal agency,
or, if the property lacks significant habitat values, sell the donated property
and use the proceeds to protect land with important wildlife values.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;contributions&quot;&gt;Contributions&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The RMEF may provide funding to state or federal agencies or another nonprofit
organization to assist them with their wildlife habitat protection or public
access efforts. Their contributions often generate additional habitat dollars
from matching grant programs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;land-exchanges&quot;&gt;Land Exchanges&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The RMEF may assist a government agency or a private landowner in exchanging
lands. These exchanges typically take place when an agency has wildlife habitat
lands it wants to acquire. Many exchanges will result in an increase of lands
that are open for the public to enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;associated-acres&quot;&gt;Associated Acres&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the RMEF protects land, those benefits often extend to associated, leased
grazing lands connected to the acquisition. This often results in additional
benefits to wildlife through improved grazing systems and livestock
redistribution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;habitat-stewardship-programs&quot;&gt;Habitat Stewardship Programs&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Providing high quality habitat (food, water, cover and space) is key to ensuring
the future of elk and other wildlife. Research and management projects help
manage elk in ways that guarantee productive herds and provide hunter
opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;habitat-stewardship-program-elements&quot;&gt;Habitat Stewardship Program Elements&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The RMEF’s Habitat Stewardship Program is comprised of three elements: &lt;strong&gt;habitat
enhancement, wildlife management and research.&lt;/strong&gt; Financial support for the
program comes from RMEF volunteers who raise funds through local chapter events
for project grants. The RMEF then works with biologists and land managers to
fund projects that will provide wildlife the best bang for the buck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;ensuring-a-future-for-elk&quot;&gt;Ensuring a Future for Elk&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The RMEF helps ensure that North America’s elk will remain abundant and healthy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;by working with federal, state, provincial and tribal land managers as well as
private landowners to restore healthy habitat on public and private lands&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;by supporting management and research efforts by state and provincial
agencies, universities and private organizations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;habitat-enhancement&quot;&gt;Habitat Enhancement&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fire suppression, invasive weeds, conifer encroachment and drought all degrade
elk habitat. Some, like drought, are just nature’s way. Others, like fire
suppression and weeds, are a direct result of human actions. Using tools such as
&lt;strong&gt;prescribed burning, thinning, fertilization, seeding, water developments,
noxious weed treatments and fencing&lt;/strong&gt;, they are reversing the effects of these
impacts on elk country. Many of their projects enhance habitat on public and
private lands where elk already exist; some are designed to encourage elk to
move onto public lands and away from ranchers’ crops and haystacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;wildlife-management&quot;&gt;Wildlife Management&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Providing grants for studies and tools such as new elk census techniques, and
telemetry studies to determine habitat use and migration routes, are other ways
that the RMEF helps wildlife managers enhance and maintain wild, free-ranging
elk populations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;research&quot;&gt;Research&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The RMEF understands that the future of our wild elk herds depends on good
science. Funding projects that research critical factors such as nutritional
needs of elk, predation and disease provides biologists with sound, scientific
data for effective wildlife and habitat management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;elk-restoration-programs&quot;&gt;Elk Restoration Programs&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is perhaps no higher calling for a conservation organization than to
restore extirpated wildlife species back to their historic ranges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;feasibility-studies&quot;&gt;Feasibility Studies&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that in mind, in 1990 the Rocky Mountain Elk Foundation began funding
feasibility studies to determine if wild, free-ranging elk still had a place in
some of their former eastern habitats. Partnering with state wildlife agencies
and universities, they asked three important questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can the habitat support elk?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How will restoring elk affect the local economy and hunting?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And finally, will local citizens accept a restored elk herd?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;repopulating-historic-range&quot;&gt;Repopulating Historic Range&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once a feasibility study is completed and a restoration project is approved by
the state wildlife agency and affected landowners, the RMEF and its volunteers
help trap and transfer wild elk from a source herd to their ancestral grounds.
All elk trapped are tested for seven diseases, including brucellosis and
bluetongue, before leaving the trap site. Healthy source herds have been used in
Arizona, Kansas, New Mexico, North Dakota, Oregon, Utah and Alberta’s Elk Island
National Park.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;monitoring-ensures-success&quot;&gt;Monitoring Ensures Success&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once elk reach their new destination, it’s up to the participating wildlife
agency to decide whether they are held in acclimation pens for a few months or
released directly into the wild. Regardless, after they hit the ground the elk
are monitored for three to five years to study such things as movement patterns
and calf survival to ensure proper management of the herd and their habitat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;restoration-efforts-so-far&quot;&gt;Restoration Efforts So Far&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RMEF helped launch successful elk restorations in Wisconsin in 1995, Kentucky in
1997, Tennessee in 2000, Ontario in 1998, the Great Smoky Mountains National
Park in 2001, Missouri in 2011, Virginia in 2012 and West Virginia in 2016. In
addition, RMEF has funded completed feasibility studies in Illinois, Maryland,
New York and West Virginia. The state agencies use the study data to determine
whether or not to restore elk to their respective state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;a-benefit-to-people-and-economies&quot;&gt;A Benefit to People and Economies&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, wild, free-ranging elk are making tracks in places where they haven’t for
more than a century. Local economies benefit from visitors who travel from all
over to catch a glimpse of the wily wapiti. In 2001, Kentucky held its first elk
hunt in 150 years, and Pennsylvania its first hunt in more than 70 years. In
2009, Tennessee also held its first elk hunt in 150 years. As Eastern elk herds
continue to prosper, the RMEF, its volunteers and partners will be there to
welcome calves born beneath the hardwoods, and hear bulls’ bugles echoing across
mountains and through hollows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To Learn More about the Successful Elk Restorations please visit:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dnr.wi.gov/topic/wildlifehabitat/elk.html&quot;&gt;Wisconsin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.northernontario.org/StuffOfLife/ElkRestoration/1_ElkRestoration.htm&quot;&gt;Ontario&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://fw.ky.gov/Hunt/Documents/KAwinter07elkhistory.pdf&quot;&gt;Kentucky&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tn.gov/twra/article/elk&quot;&gt;Tennessee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nps.gov/grsm/naturescience/elk.htm&quot;&gt;Great Smoky Mountains National Park&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nature.mdc.mo.gov/discover-nature/field-guide/north-american-elk-wapiti&quot;&gt;Missouri&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dgif.virginia.gov/wildlife/elk/management-plan/&quot;&gt;Virginia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wvdnr.gov/Publications/Draft_Elk_Plan.pdf&quot;&gt;West Virginia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;additional-stats&quot;&gt;Additional Stats&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Acres Protected and Enhanced
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;More than 7.4 million acres&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Number of Acres Opened and/or Secured for Public Access for Hunting and Other
Outdoor Recreation
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;More than 1.2 million acres opened and/or secured&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Number of Permanent Land Protection, Habitat Stewardship, Elk Restoration,
Conservation Education and Hunting Heritage Projects
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;More than 11,818 projects&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Number of Members
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;More than 234,000&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Number of Chapters
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;More than 500 in the United States&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Number of Volunteers
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;More than 12,000&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;giveaway-details&quot;&gt;Giveaway Details&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m giving away 3 annual supporting membership to the Rocky Mountain Elk
Foundation. This is for one year and you will have to renew if you chose to do
so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Membership includes the following benefits:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 Year subscription to Bugle (six issues)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Decal and personalized membership card&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Invitations to local events&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Discounted products and services&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Exclusive content in the members-only section of www.rmef.org&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To enter all you need to do is enter your email address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;dates-running&quot;&gt;Dates Running&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This giveaway will run from Monday March 25th, 2019 and expires on Monday April
8th, 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nine (9) winners will be selected at random on Tuesday April 9th, 2019 and a
followup blog post in regards to the winners will go live no later than
Wednesday April 10th, 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;disclaimer&quot;&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I promise to never spam you or sell your email address. The only reason the
address is collected is to notify you of winning. Once the contest is over the
data collected on all users will be deleted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;how-to-enter&quot;&gt;How to Enter&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just fill out the form located &lt;a href=&quot;https://goo.gl/forms/nJQ7dsMyP7zEWuOD3&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
It’s as simple as that.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 12:51:58 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/03/25/rmef-membership-giveaway/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/03/25/rmef-membership-giveaway/</guid>
        
        <category>conservation</category>
        
        <category>hunting</category>
        
        <category>RMEF</category>
        
        <category>elk</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>S.47 has been Signed</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;All ethics so far evolved rest upon a single premise: that the individual is
a member of a community of interdependent parts. The land ethic simply
enlarges the boundaries of the community to include soils, waters, plants and
animals, or collectively the land.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Aldo Leopold&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;President Donald Trump on Tuesday signed a massive package of public lands
legislation made up of more than 100 individual bills that were introduced by 50
senators and several U.S. House members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those include measures to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Permanently reauthorize the Land and Water Conservation Fund, with key reforms
to strengthen its state-side program;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Increase access and opportunities for hunting, fishing, and other outdoor
recreational activities on federal lands;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provide for economic development in dozens of communities through land
exchanges and conveyances;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improve western water management by increasing local control, promoting
investment, and facilitating the recovery of endangered species; and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Conserve treasured landscapes in communities, where such designations are
locally supported.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Formerly known as the &lt;em&gt;Natural Resources Management Act&lt;/em&gt;, the bipartisan bill,
S. 47, was renamed the &lt;strong&gt;John D. Dingell Jr. Conservation, Management and
Recreation Act&lt;/strong&gt; in honor of
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Dingell&quot;&gt;Dingell&lt;/a&gt;, a long-serving member of
Congress who died last month at the age of 92.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;President Trump knows that federal lands are meant to provide both peace and
prosperity for the American people, and signing this bill allows us to continue
managing public lands in a balanced way,” David Bernhardt, acting Department of
Interior secretary, said in a statement &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. “This bill is extremely beneficial
to the American people, and I look forward to working with Congress and local
communities to implement the many local conservation wins within the bill.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Highlights of the bill include permanent reauthorization of the Land and Water
Conservation Fund, expanded hunting and fishing opportunities on dozens of
national wildlife refuges and thousands more acres of other public lands, and a
provision allowing archery hunters to carry unarmed bows across National Park
Service land.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a news release &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, U.S. Sen. John Hoeven, R-N.D., said the bill also
“advances important North Dakota priorities.” Among those priorities, the bill
streamlines the process for transferring titles from the Bureau of Reclamation
to local authorities, said Hoeven, a member of the Senate Energy and Natural
Resources Committee. That aligns with legislation Hoeven introduced to transfer
the title for the Oakes Test Area to the Dickey-Sargent Irrigation District in
the southeast part of the state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bill also includes legislation Hoeven and Sen. Amy Klobuchar, D-Minn.,
introduced to improve and expand the North Country Scenic Trail, which runs from
New York to North Dakota.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The grassroots group Backcountry Hunters and Anglers called Tuesday’s signing of
the bill a “significant victory for public lands sportsmen and women.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Together, the public lands grassroots nation rose up to ensure the passage of
this historic bill,” Land Tawney, BHA president and CEO, said in a statement
&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. “We wrote letters, we made phone calls, we met with our elected officials
and we traveled from across the country to Washington, D.C., and together we
made our voices heard. Today, we can celebrate a victory that has been years in
the making.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sen. Lisa Murkowski, R-Alaska, chairman of the Senate Energy and Natural
Resources Committee, said the president’s effort to achieve U.S. energy
dominance while working with Congress to create a conservation legacy “exceeds
the accomplishments of his recent predecessors” with the signing of the lands
package.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This law will benefit every state and clear the deck of issues that we’ve been
working to resolve for years,” Murkowski said in a statement &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:4&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:4&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. “From
providing access for sportsmen to creating new economic opportunities for local
communities, this is a good, balanced measure. We built it through a team effort
that drew strong support from both parties in both chambers. Today is a triumph
for good process and good policy, and this bill is a win for Alaskans and all
Americans.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;additional-reading&quot;&gt;Additional Reading&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.govtrack.us/congress/bills/116/s47&quot;&gt;“S. 47 — 116th Congress: John D. Dingell, Jr. Conservation, Management, and Recreation Act.” www.GovTrack.us. 2019. March 13, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/statement-by-the-president-29/&quot;&gt;Statement by the President&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/bernhardt-applauds-signing-bipartisan-public-lands-bill&quot;&gt;Statement from Department of Interior Secretary&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hoeven.senate.gov/news/news-releases/hoeven-president-signs-bipartisan-lands-package-into-law2019&quot;&gt;Statement from U.S. Sen. John Hoeven, R-N.D.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.backcountryhunters.org/bha_celebrates_public_lands_bill_s_passage_into_law&quot;&gt;Statement from Backcountry Hunters and Anglers&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:4&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.murkowski.senate.gov/press/release/president-trump-signs-sweeping-lands-package-into-law-&quot;&gt;Statement from U.S. Sen. Lisa Murkowski, R-AK&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:4&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 00:33:44 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/03/13/s.47-has-been-signed/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/03/13/s.47-has-been-signed/</guid>
        
        <category>conservation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Conservation - One more Step</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We abuse land because we regard it as a commodity belonging to us. When we see
land as a community to which we belong, we may begin to use it with love and
respect.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Aldo Leopold&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A vote by the U.S. House of Representatives on Tuesday supported a massive
package of conservation and public access bills that permanently reauthorizes
the Land and Water Conservation Fund and advances other key measures, edging
hunters, anglers and other outdoor enthusiasts closer to a hard-won and
long-awaited victory. The legislation now heads to the president’s desk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the most sweeping conservation leglislation in over a decade, protecting
millions of acres of land and hundreds of miles of wild rivers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Natural Resources Management Act (S. 47)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; encompasses the consensus
priorities of sportsmen and women as well as a bipartisan cadre of senators who
have worked to ensure the legislation’s survival. Senate Majority Leader Mitch
McConnell’s (R-KY), Senate Minority Leader Chuck Schumer’s (D-NY) and Sen. Lisa
Murkowski’s (R-AK) ongoing efforts that began last Congress paid off with
today’s overwhelming 363-62 with 6 non-votes&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; vote in support of the measure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The House vote was a resounding affirmation of bipartisan support for the
legislation. The bill includes measures sought by lawmakers from most every
state, including a smattering of pet projects, and might also be an indication
that to reach broad consensus in Washington, D.C., the sausage-making requires a
serving or two of locally sourced pork.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The House passed the bill, under suspension of its rules, which means it
required a two-thirds vote of approval.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Key features of &lt;strong&gt;S. 47&lt;/strong&gt; include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Permanent reauthorization of the Land and Water Conservation Fund with 3
percent dedicated to securing hunting and fishing access opportunities on
public lands and waters.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Frank and Jeanne Moore Wild Steelhead Special Management Area.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Methow Valley permanent mineral withdrawal.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;California Desert Protection and Recreation Act.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cerro del Yuta and Rio San Antonio wilderness areas.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reauthorization of the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service’s Partners for Fish and
Wildlife program at current funding levels of $51.6 million until FY2022.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reauthorization of Neotropical Migratory Bird Conservation Act at $6.5 million
until FY2022, a $2.6 million increase of funding from currently enacted
levels.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Authorization for hunters with archery equipment to cross National Park
Service lands by foot or horseback.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The masses are awakening, and the public lands revolution is growing,”
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.snewsnet.com/tag/backcountry-hunters-anglers&quot;&gt;Backcountry Hunters &amp;amp;
Anglers&lt;/a&gt; President and
CEO Land Tawney said. “Today’s vote by the House of Representatives, coming on
the heels of the Senate’s overwhelming support of S. 47 earlier this month,
proves without a doubt that citizens’ voices do count and our nation’s
congressional leaders can come together to advance meaningful bipartisan
legislation.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://fusion94.org/blog/2019-02-14/a-partial-win-for-conservation/&quot;&gt;act’s passage through the
Senate&lt;/a&gt;
and now the House comes at a time when politics are particularly contentious and
split. But because it touches on all 50 states and appeases environmentalists,
anglers, sportsmen, and every other variety of recreationists, the legislation
received support from both sides of the aisle, with little debate on the House
floor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;voting-breakdown&quot;&gt;Voting Breakdown&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned earlier the voting was 363-62 with 6 non-votes.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;780&quot; height=&quot;9150&quot; src=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/e/2PACX-1vRVajrXa8IY5mT6O1t7Wn8oBgpTtdbQFuvYdzXkTLCJ-wrcN8gqv4I2dS-_JlcQtzRDd8F1r8OX8fOp/pubhtml?gid=1816224076&amp;amp;single=true&amp;amp;widget=true&amp;amp;headers=false&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.congress.gov/bill/116th-congress/senate-bill/47&quot;&gt;S.47 - Natural Resources Management Act&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.govtrack.us/congress/votes/116-2019/h95&quot;&gt;How they voted&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 22:40:09 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/02/27/conservation-one-more-step/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/02/27/conservation-one-more-step/</guid>
        
        <category>conservation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Elk Bolognese</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Bolognese sauce (UK: /ˌbɒləˈneɪz, -ˈnɛz/, US: /ˌboʊlənˈjeɪz/;[1] known in
Italian as ragù alla bolognese, pronounced [raˈɡu alla boloɲˈɲeːze; -eːse],
ragù bolognese, or simply ragù) is a meat-based sauce originating from
Bologna, Italy, hence the name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless of the season there isn’t much that warms a soul better than a big
plate of pasta topped with a classic, slow-cooked &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bolognese_sauce&quot; title=&quot;Bolognese Sauce&quot;&gt;Bolognese
Sauce&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a sauce with rules. It is built on a base of onion, carrot and celery.
Nor does it have lots of herbs in it. The sauce contains dairy products. And
tomato, while present, is not the star of the sauce. The meat is. And to make a
real Bolognese, it must cook a &lt;strong&gt;long, long time&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with most wild game recipes, I have tweaked the classic just a bit to make it
work with elk. Since elk is leaner than the traditional mixture of ground beef
chuck and ground pork in most Bolognese sauce recipes, I add a bit of fat in the
form of diced bacon (although one could use pancetta). The bacon itself breaks
down during the relatively long cooking time, so you don’t really notice it in
the final dish, but the flavor and texture that the small amount of pork fat
really adds to the dish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 pounds ground elk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6-8 slices bacon (diced) (pancetta could also be used here)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 medium onion (finely chopped)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 stalk celery (finely chopped)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 large carrot (finely chopped)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 shallot (finely chopped)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 cloves garlic (minced)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 tablespoons butter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 tablespoons olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tablespoons tomato paste&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup beef broth&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup dry red wine&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 can (28 ounce) San Marzano tomatoes (crushed)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1-2 bay leaf&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1⁄2 teaspoon black pepper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tablespoon dried oregano&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tablespoon dried basil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3/4 teaspoon red pepper flakes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup whole milk or cream (you will need to use double cream to prevent any
separating &lt;em&gt;(48–60% fat content)&lt;/em&gt; )&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 ½ pounds dry Tagliatelle pasta&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parmigiano-Reggiano or Pecorino Romano cheese for grating&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;instructions&quot;&gt;Instructions&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;prep-work&quot;&gt;Prep Work&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start by either chopping or dicing your basic ingredients. This would include
your bacon, onion, celery, carrot, shallot and garlic. I also portion out my dry
ingredients in small stainless steel portion cups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/ingredients.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; height=&quot;70%&quot; width=&quot;70%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;captions&quot;&gt;
Prep Work Done.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;cooking-instructions&quot;&gt;Cooking Instructions&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start by adding the olive oil and diced bacon to a heavy pot (an enameled cast
iron pot is perfect) using medium heat. Render the bacon (or pancetta) until
crisp. Next add the diced onion, carrot, celery and shallot and cook for
approximately fifteen minutes, stirring often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add the ground elk and cook till it is browned through, this should take about
15 minutes. Add the garlic and raise the heat to medium-high then add the wine
and beef broth. Cook sauce until wine and broth are mostly evaporated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turn down the heat to a simmer and add oregano, basil, salt, pepper, and red
pepper flakes. Let this cook for approximately 20 minutes. Now add the crushed
tomatoes and tomato paste and bring heat up until you have a boil. After a few
minutes, reduce the heat to a simmer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let the sauce simmer (very slowly) partially covered for about 2 to 4 hours (the
longer the better), do stir occasionally to prevent sticking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/sauce.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; height=&quot;70%&quot; width=&quot;70%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;captions&quot;&gt;
Bolognese is done.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About 5 to 10 minutes before serving, add milk or cream and butter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just before the sauce is finished, bring one gallon of water to a boil, add two
tablespoons of salt and the pasta. Cook for eight to 10 minutes or until the
pasta is al dente. Top with the bolognese sauce and cheese just before serving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/final_product.webp&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; height=&quot;70%&quot; width=&quot;70%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;captions&quot;&gt;
The Final Product.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:28:13 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/02/20/elk-bolognese/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/02/20/elk-bolognese/</guid>
        
        <category>elk</category>
        
        <category>bolognese</category>
        
        <category>cooking</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Conservation and Hunting</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I recognize the right and duty of this generation to develop and use the
natural resources of our land; but I do not recognize the right to waste them,
or to rob, by wasteful use, the generations that come after us.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Theodore Roosevelt President of the United States (#26)&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;hunting-and-conservation&quot;&gt;Hunting and Conservation&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;My views on Conservation have been formed by actively hunting, fishing, and
spending time in the outdoors for close to 45 years now.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;me&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our nation’s early years, there were few laws protecting fish and wildlife
and our wildlife resources took a heavy toll. Market hunters took fish and
wildlife &lt;strong&gt;at will&lt;/strong&gt; while habitat disappeared under plow and roads, resulting
in devastating reductions in wildlife populations. Some species, like the
passenger pigeon, were taken to the point of no return; others such as bison,
white-tailed deer and wild turkeys, were pushed to the edge extinction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the tides turned for conservation, important laws were passed, including the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Migratory_Bird_Treaty_Act_of_1918&quot;&gt;Migratory Bird Treaty Act of
1918&lt;/a&gt;, the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Federal_Duck_Stamp&quot;&gt;Migratory Bird Hunting and Conservation Stamp Act of
1934&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dingell%E2%80%93Johnson_Act&quot;&gt;Federal Aid in
Sport Fish Restoration Act of
1950&lt;/a&gt;. Collectively,
these acts laid the foundation for what inspired the North American Model of
Wildlife Conservation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;north-american-model-of-wildlife-conservation&quot;&gt;North American Model of Wildlife Conservation&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Across North America, hunting was a largely unregulated activity for individuals
and commercial entities until the 1800’s, when citizens began to ask whether
wildlife populations could continue at healthy levels without checks on hunting.
The legal framework that has since developed grew out of a set of principles now
known as the &lt;strong&gt;North American Model of Wildlife Conservation&lt;/strong&gt;. Seven features
make the North American model distinct.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wildlife is a public resource&lt;/strong&gt;. In the Unites States, wildlife is considered a public resource, independent of the land or water where wildlife may live. Government at various levels have a role in managing that resource on behalf of all citizens and to ensure the long-term sustainability of wildlife populations.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Markets for game are eliminated&lt;/strong&gt;. Before wildlife protection laws were enacted, commercial operations decimated populations of many species. Making it illegal to buy and sell meat and parts of game and nongame species removed a huge threat to the survival of those species. A market in furbearers continues as a highly regulated activity, often to manage invasive wildlife.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Allocation of wildlife by law&lt;/strong&gt;. Wildlife is a public resource managed by government. As a result, access to wildlife for hunting is through legal mechanisms such as set hunting seasons, bag limits, license requirements, etc.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wildlife can only be killed for a legitimate purpose&lt;/strong&gt;. Wildlife is a shared resource that must not be wasted. The law prohibits killing wildlife for frivolous reasons.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wildlife is an international resource&lt;/strong&gt;. Some species, such as migratory birds cross international boundaries. Treaties such as the Migratory Bird Treaty and CITES recognize a shared responsibility to manage these species across national boundaries.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Science is the proper tool for discharge of wildlife policy&lt;/strong&gt;. In order to manage wildlife as a shared resource fairly, objectively, and knowledgeably, decisions must be based on sound science such as annual waterfowl population surveys and the work of professional wildlife biologists.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The democracy of hunting&lt;/strong&gt;. In keeping with democratic principles, government allocates access to wildlife without regard for wealth, prestige, or land ownership.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carrying on the theme above here are 5 fairly concrete examples of how
hunting/sportsmen work(s) in conjunction with Conservation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In 1907, only 41,000 elk remained in North America. Thanks to the money and hard work invested by hunters to restore and conserve habitat, today there are more than 1 million.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In 1900, only 500,000 whitetails remained. Thanks to conservation work spearheaded by hunters, today there are more than 32 million.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In 1900, only 100,000 wild turkeys remained. Thanks to hunters, today there are over 7 million.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In 1901, few ducks remained. Thanks to hunters’ efforts to restore and conserve wetlands, today there are more than 44 million.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In 1950, only 12,000 pronghorn remained. Thanks to hunters, today there are more than 1.1 million.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 5 species listed above were almost completely wiped out to to market hunting
and really only came back due to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pittman%E2%80%93Robertson_Federal_Aid_in_Wildlife_Restoration_Act&quot;&gt;Federal Aid in Wildlife Restoration Act of
1937&lt;/a&gt;.
This law, commonly referred to the Pittman-Robertson Act created an excise tax
that provides funds to each state to manage such animals and their habitats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Pittman-Robertson Act (P-R) increased an existing 10-percent gun-and-bullet
tax by one percent and dedicated the proceeds to the USFWS to apportion to
states during a time when Congress was slashing taxes. It has generated more
than $11 billion for conservation since 1939.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the P-R’s greatest strengths is its $3-to-$1 federal-state match, which
requires states to pony up $1 for every three federal grant dollars. This
practice discourages state legislators from sweeping revenues generated by
licenses and fees—which are state wildlife agencies’ primary source of
funding—into the general fund.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of going into the U.S. Treasury as it had done in the past, the money is
kept separate and is given to the Secretary of the Interior to distribute to the
States. The Secretary determines how much to give to each state based on a
formula that takes into account both the area of the state and its number of
licensed hunters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how much money does this actually mean? Well here are the breakdowns for 2018
when you combine the Federal Aid in Wildlife Restoration Act of 1937 with the
Federal Aid in Sport Fish Restoration Act of 1950 &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;STATE&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;TOTAL - SPORT FISH RESTORATION (FY18)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;TOTAL - ALL WILDLIFE FUNDS (FY18)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;TOTAL - ALL FUNDS (FY18)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;ALABAMA&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$6,151,179&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$19,360,421&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$25,511,600&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;ALASKA&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$17,595,874&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$33,455,771&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$51,051,645&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;AMERICAN SAMOA&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$1,173,058&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$1,328,563&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$2,501,621&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;ARIZONA&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$7,154,503&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$22,080,003&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$29,234,506&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;ARKANSAS&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$5,348,981&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$13,221,723&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$18,570,704&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;CALIFORNIA&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$16,513,733&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$26,037,993&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$42,551,726&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;COLORADO&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$9,143,673&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$19,872,123&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$29,015,796&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;CONNECTICUT&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$3,519,175&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$5,901,190&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$9,420,365&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;DELAWARE&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$3,519,175&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$4,785,824&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$8,304,999&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$1,173,058&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$0&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$1,173,058&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;FLORIDA&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$12,236,611&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$14,351,398&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$26,588,009&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;GEORGIA&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$8,041,424&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$23,213,465&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$31,254,889&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;GUAM&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$1,173,058&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$1,328,563&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$2,501,621&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;HAWAII&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$3,519,175&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$4,785,824&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$8,304,999&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;IDAHO&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$6,430,284&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$15,474,320&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$21,904,604&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;ILLINOIS&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$6,593,209&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$16,335,080&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$22,928,289&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;INDIANA&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$4,577,731&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$13,573,699&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$18,151,430&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;IOWA&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$4,513,130&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$11,515,178&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$16,028,308&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;KANSAS&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$4,981,927&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$14,646,057&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$19,627,984&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;KENTUCKY&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$5,198,763&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$14,127,290&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$19,326,053&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;LOUISIANA&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$6,908,171&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$15,884,383&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$22,792,554&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;MAINE&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$3,519,175&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$8,055,283&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$11,574,458&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;MARYLAND&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$3,519,175&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$7,754,551&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$11,273,726&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;MASSACHUSETTS&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$3,519,175&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$7,986,372&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$11,505,547&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;MICHIGAN&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$10,692,452&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$24,296,525&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$34,988,977&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;MINNESOTA&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$12,500,370&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$23,400,370&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$35,900,740&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;MISSISSIPPI&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$4,009,209&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$12,144,757&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$16,153,966&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;MISSOURI&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$7,677,750&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$21,117,103&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$28,794,853&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;MONTANA&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$8,648,987&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$21,131,270&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$29,780,257&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;N. MARIANA ISLANDS&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$1,173,058&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$1,328,563&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$2,501,621&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;NEBRASKA&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$4,483,366&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$12,833,330&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$17,316,696&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;NEVADA&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$4,974,601&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$13,948,153&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$18,922,754&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;NEW HAMPSHIRE&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$3,519,175&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$4,785,824&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$8,304,999&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;NEW JERSEY&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$3,519,175&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$7,986,372&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$11,505,547&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;NEW MEXICO&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$6,244,495&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$15,787,434&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$22,031,929&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;NEW YORK&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$7,820,180&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$20,862,345&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$28,682,525&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;NORTH CAROLINA&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$10,344,499&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$21,338,737&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$31,683,236&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;NORTH DAKOTA&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$4,130,618&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$11,377,784&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$15,508,402&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;OHIO&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$6,898,966&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$16,457,632&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$23,356,598&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;OKLAHOMA&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$7,695,368&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$19,907,732&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$27,603,100&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;OREGON&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$7,820,246&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$17,690,588&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$25,510,834&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;PENNSYLVANIA&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$8,571,622&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$28,157,633&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$36,729,255&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;PUERTO RICO&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$3,519,175&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$3,452,263&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$6,971,438&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;RHODE ISLAND&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$3,519,175&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$4,785,824&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$8,304,999&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;SOUTH CAROLINA&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$4,899,188&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$10,678,793&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$15,577,981&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;SOUTH DAKOTA&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$4,490,053&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$13,775,104&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$18,265,157&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;TENNESSEE&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$7,457,271&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$22,544,767&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$30,002,038&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;TEXAS&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$17,595,874&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$36,656,319&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$54,252,193&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;UTAH&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$6,405,939&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$14,616,342&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$21,022,281&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;VERMONT&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$3,519,175&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$4,785,824&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$8,304,999&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;VIRGIN ISLANDS&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$1,173,058&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$1,328,563&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$2,501,621&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;VIRGINIA&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$5,204,846&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$14,176,335&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$19,381,181&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;WASHINGTON&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$7,112,530&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$15,120,458&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$22,232,988&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;WEST VIRGINIA&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$3,519,175&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$8,209,596&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$11,728,771&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;WISCONSIN&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$11,424,513&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$23,542,090&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$34,966,603&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;WYOMING&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$5,329,957&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$13,861,148&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$19,191,105&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;TOTAL&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$351,917,483&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$797,160,652&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$1,149,078,135&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here’s that data represented visually:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So in total, that’s $1.15 billion dollars going directly back into conservation
efforts from sportsmen in 2018. Which comes to approximately $10 billion in
spending by sportsmen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In comparison, in 2017 the Sierra Club received $68 million dollars in total
contributions and spent $63 million dollars on program services. Essentially
sportsmen from Michigan and North Carolina &lt;strong&gt;combined&lt;/strong&gt; contributed the same
amount as the Sierra Club in total. I’m not trying to paint the Sierra Club as a
bad organization at all. They simply just can’t do enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the first annual apportionment of $890,000 in 1939 by the U.S. Fish and
Wildlife Service (USFWS), the agency has distributed more than $21 billion from
the two federal excise taxes for state conservation and recreation projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;881.5888697855398&quot; height=&quot;503&quot; seamless=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/e/2PACX-1vRQdMnUYWKzIKdOgPCl70vuGQU9t5wlg_MCEgqcLJk9C6YpvD2hPZV-TQ0xKw2ZnKHG3wM-4KXxTd4Z/pubchart?oid=207623445&amp;amp;format=image&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;captions&quot;&gt;
This chart shows the trend of total P-R apportionment per fiscal year, from 2009 to 2018.&lt;br /&gt;
(Data via &lt;a href=&quot;https://wsfrprograms.fws.gov/Subpages/GrantPrograms/WR/WR_Funding.htm&quot;&gt;USFWS&lt;/a&gt;)
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buying licenses, stamps and tags to legally hunt or fish in America is an
essential and necessary means to supporting wildlife conservation. As a matter
of record the recipient state wildlife agencies have matched these funds with
approximately $6.7 billion throughout the years, primarily through those hunting
and fishing license revenues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;next-steps&quot;&gt;Next Steps&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;expanding-the-excise-tax&quot;&gt;Expanding the Excise Tax&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how can we as sportsmen increase that number? Well, for one, if the excise
tax provided by the Pittman-Robertson act was increased to 15% then that would
raise the total amount to $1.5 billion annually. Seems pretty straight forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some experts think it’s time to expand P-R taxes to more hunting and
shooting-related products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whit Fosburgh, president and CEO of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.trcp.org/&quot;&gt;Teddy Roosevelt Conservation
Partnership&lt;/a&gt;, thinks hunters should lobby to get items
such as treestands, reloading equipment, powder, and primers included in P-R to
increase the revenues that give them leverage in influencing conservation
policy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whitney Tilt a consultant on natural resource conservation wrote a post &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;
over on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.perc.org&quot;&gt;PERC — the Property and Environment Research
Center&lt;/a&gt; asking whether or not should mountain bikers,
kayakers, and other recreationalists pay an excise tax to help fund outdoor
recreation?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This in essence would extend the P-R tax to “outdoor products you can buy at REI
— bicycles, camping gear, tents and following that P-R model” would benefit
everyone, especially wildlife.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;passing-new-legislation&quot;&gt;Passing New Legislation&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, there are three bills currently making their way through the
legislative branch that would dedicate more money both directly, and indirectly,
to hunting and shooting sports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.congress.gov/bill/115th-congress/house-bill/788&quot;&gt;HR 788&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Target Practice and Marksmanship Training Support Act&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sponsored by Rep. Duncan Hunter, R-California, this would allow P-R funds to pay
up to 90 percent, rather than the current 75 percent, of costs in acquiring land
for expanding, or constructing, public shooting ranges. It would also lower the
P-R match to 10 percent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By lowering the P-R match to 10 percent, it also gives states more ability to
award grants for shooting ranges and hunter education programs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Idaho Fish and Game Director Virgil Moore, who is also the president of the
Association of Fish &amp;amp; Wildlife Agencies states that this will allow State
agencies to form public-private ventures to enhance public access, so a
privately-owned shooting range could qualify for a grant if its proposal met
certain public-access criteria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“As I review budget requests, I’m looking for bang for my buck,” Moore said,
noting grant applications are more likely to receive IDFG approval if they
involve coalitions offering multiple benefits.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;status&quot;&gt;Status&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;info “”
It’s been in the House Subcommittee since March 2017 although &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.congress.gov/bill/115th-congress/senate-bill/593&quot;&gt;S. 593&lt;/a&gt; appears to be an identical bill currently before the Senate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.congress.gov/bill/115th-congress/house-bill/2591&quot;&gt;HR 2591&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Modernizing The Pittman-Robertson Fund For Tomorrow’s Needs Act of 2017&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sponsored by Rep. Austin Scott, R-Georgia, this legislation would authorize P-R
funds to recruit, retain, and reactivate hunters and recreational shooters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jeff Crane, &lt;a href=&quot;http://congressionalsportsmen.org/about/staff/jeff-crane&quot;&gt;President of the Congressional Sportsmen’s
Caucus&lt;/a&gt; said P-R funds
would complement marketing campaigns by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://home.nra.org/&quot;&gt;National Rifle Association
(NRA)&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nssf.org/&quot;&gt;National Shooting Sports Foundation
(NSSF)&lt;/a&gt;. “They have good programs and want to capitalize
on this,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allocating P-R funds for marketing is fine if money for wildlife restoration
remains intact, said Mike Leahy, senior manager of public lands conservation and
sportsmen policy at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nwf.org/About-Us/Our-Experts&quot;&gt;National Wildlife
Federation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“We think those ought to start small, by redirecting some money from hunter
education to marketing, until we know more about how effective these ideas are,
how much they cost, and how great the need is. Let’s see what the return on
investment is before we start pulling money from wildlife biologists and habitat
managers.” Leahy said.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;status-1&quot;&gt;Status&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;info “”
It was introduced to the House and the House Natural Resources Committee on 05/22/2017. On 09/12/2018 it was passed/agreed to in House. On 09/17/2018 it was received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.congress.gov/bill/115th-congress/house-bill/4647&quot;&gt;HR 4647&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Recovering America’s Wildlife Act&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sponsored by Rep. Jeff Fortenberry, R-Nebraska, this would redirect $1.3 billion
in existing royalties and fees annually from drilling and mining on federal
lands and waters to conserve &lt;strong&gt;“the full array of fish and wildlife.”&lt;/strong&gt; It’s
also been in the House Natural Resources Committee since February.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bill would “intermingle” P-R funds with, potentially, $1.3 billion earmarked
to “provide more money for species that don’t have stable funding,” Idaho’s Fish
and Game Director Virgil Moore said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This will indirectly benefit hunters who ideally want P-R allocations dedicated
to game animals, Mike Leahy said, because habitat is habitat. HR 4647 “would
give states the money they need for wildlife” using little P-R money, he said.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This potentially will impact hunters because a non-game animal can still be
designated endangered — such as the timber rattler in New York’s Hudson
Highlands — thereby imposing restrictions on hunting lands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HR 4647’s goal is to “keep species from becoming endangered” and avoid access
restrictions, Nick Wiley, chief conservation officer for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ducks.org&quot;&gt;Ducks
Unlimited&lt;/a&gt;, and former executive director of the Florida
Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission said. “Restricting access is rarely a
good thing. It’s all about the habitat.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;status-2&quot;&gt;Status&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;info “”
It was introduced to the House on 12/14/2017 and on 02/15/2018 Subcommittee Hearings were held by the House Natural Resources Subcommittee on Federal Lands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;concluding-thoughts&quot;&gt;Concluding Thoughts&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conservation can often be challenging as there will never be enough funding to
cover all the needs. Yet, we can (and must) do more to conserve fish, wildlife
and their habitat to ensure the future of hunting, fishing, and outdoor
recreational activities for subsequent generations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;additional-information&quot;&gt;Additional Information&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;note “”
fusion94.org is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and linking to Amazon.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I began this article with a quote from Theodore Roosevelt Jr. TR was an American
statesman, &lt;strong&gt;conservationist and writer&lt;/strong&gt; who served as the 26th president of
the United States from 1901 to 1909. He previously served as the 25th vice
president of the United States from March to September 1901 and as the 33rd
governor of New York from 1899 to 1900. As a leader of the Republican Party
during this time, he became a driving force for the Progressive Era in the
United States in the early 20th century. His face is depicted on Mount Rushmore,
alongside those of George Washington, Thomas Jefferson, and Abraham Lincoln. In
polls of historians and political scientists, Roosevelt is generally ranked as
one of the &lt;strong&gt;five best presidents&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roosevelt brought his desire to address the common interests of citizens to the
West. He successfully led efforts to organize ranchers to address problems of
overgrazing and other shared concerns; his work resulted in the formation of the
Little Missouri Stockmen’s Association. He felt compelled to promote
conservation and was able to form the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.boone-crockett.org/&quot;&gt;Boone and Crockett
Club&lt;/a&gt;, whose primary goal was the conservation
of large game animals and their habitats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in learning more about Teddy Roosevelt and his views on
Conservation and Hunting I would recommend the following books:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B01IBOSK1W/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B01IBOSK1W&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=fusion94-20&amp;amp;linkId=f613762e50970e93efb1589bee6acdd1&quot;&gt;Hunting Trips of a Ranchman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00NHZK0KA/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00NHZK0KA&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=fusion94-20&amp;amp;linkId=9b0a0a0370d7139467d426ac34750ba2&quot;&gt;Ranch Life and the Hunting-Trail&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00UPRZ3GO/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00UPRZ3GO&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=fusion94-20&amp;amp;linkId=03ce299d0686a17a9fba25f19ef4f24c&quot;&gt;The Wilderness Hunter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also to note is that the Kindle versions of these 3 books are all priced at $0.99&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;additional-data-pointscharts&quot;&gt;Additional Data Points/Charts&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;1192.9123989218328&quot; height=&quot;1580&quot; seamless=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/e/2PACX-1vRQdMnUYWKzIKdOgPCl70vuGQU9t5wlg_MCEgqcLJk9C6YpvD2hPZV-TQ0xKw2ZnKHG3wM-4KXxTd4Z/pubchart?oid=145527899&amp;amp;format=interactive&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;captions&quot;&gt;
This interactive chart shows the trend of total Federal Aid in Wildlife Restoration Act of 1937 with the Federal Aid in Sport Fish Restoration Act of 1950 apportionment in 2018 broken down by state.&lt;br /&gt;
(Data via &lt;a href=&quot;https://wsfrprograms.fws.gov/Subpages/GrantPrograms/WR/WR_Funding.htm&quot;&gt;USFWS&lt;/a&gt;)
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;1269.0888697855398&quot; height=&quot;2408&quot; seamless=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/e/2PACX-1vRQdMnUYWKzIKdOgPCl70vuGQU9t5wlg_MCEgqcLJk9C6YpvD2hPZV-TQ0xKw2ZnKHG3wM-4KXxTd4Z/pubchart?oid=7104493&amp;amp;format=interactive&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;captions&quot;&gt;
This interactive chart shows the trend of total P-R apportionment per fiscal year, from 1939 to 2018.&lt;br /&gt;
(Data via &lt;a href=&quot;https://wsfrprograms.fws.gov/Subpages/GrantPrograms/WR/WR_Funding.htm&quot;&gt;USFWS&lt;/a&gt;)
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;the-next-series-of-charts-has-the-p-r-data-broken-down-in-10-year-increments&quot;&gt;The next series of charts has the P-R data broken down in 10 year increments.&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;881.5888697855398&quot; height=&quot;503&quot; seamless=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/e/2PACX-1vRQdMnUYWKzIKdOgPCl70vuGQU9t5wlg_MCEgqcLJk9C6YpvD2hPZV-TQ0xKw2ZnKHG3wM-4KXxTd4Z/pubchart?oid=754117277&amp;amp;format=image&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;captions&quot;&gt;
This chart shows the trend of total P-R apportionment per fiscal year, from 1939 to 1948.&lt;br /&gt;
(Data via &lt;a href=&quot;https://wsfrprograms.fws.gov/Subpages/GrantPrograms/WR/WR_Funding.htm&quot;&gt;USFWS&lt;/a&gt;)
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;881.5888697855398&quot; height=&quot;503&quot; seamless=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/e/2PACX-1vRQdMnUYWKzIKdOgPCl70vuGQU9t5wlg_MCEgqcLJk9C6YpvD2hPZV-TQ0xKw2ZnKHG3wM-4KXxTd4Z/pubchart?oid=279600770&amp;amp;format=image&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;captions&quot;&gt;
This chart shows the trend of total P-R apportionment per fiscal year, from 1949 to 1958.&lt;br /&gt;
(Data via &lt;a href=&quot;https://wsfrprograms.fws.gov/Subpages/GrantPrograms/WR/WR_Funding.htm&quot;&gt;USFWS&lt;/a&gt;)
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;881.5888697855398&quot; height=&quot;503&quot; seamless=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/e/2PACX-1vRQdMnUYWKzIKdOgPCl70vuGQU9t5wlg_MCEgqcLJk9C6YpvD2hPZV-TQ0xKw2ZnKHG3wM-4KXxTd4Z/pubchart?oid=831488591&amp;amp;format=image&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;captions&quot;&gt;
This chart shows the trend of total P-R apportionment per fiscal year, from 1959 to 1968.&lt;br /&gt;
(Data via &lt;a href=&quot;https://wsfrprograms.fws.gov/Subpages/GrantPrograms/WR/WR_Funding.htm&quot;&gt;USFWS&lt;/a&gt;)
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;881.5888697855398&quot; height=&quot;503&quot; seamless=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/e/2PACX-1vRQdMnUYWKzIKdOgPCl70vuGQU9t5wlg_MCEgqcLJk9C6YpvD2hPZV-TQ0xKw2ZnKHG3wM-4KXxTd4Z/pubchart?oid=1526765153&amp;amp;format=image&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;captions&quot;&gt;
This chart shows the trend of total P-R apportionment per fiscal year, from 1969 to 1978.&lt;br /&gt;
(Data via &lt;a href=&quot;https://wsfrprograms.fws.gov/Subpages/GrantPrograms/WR/WR_Funding.htm&quot;&gt;USFWS&lt;/a&gt;)
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;881.5888697855398&quot; height=&quot;503&quot; seamless=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/e/2PACX-1vRQdMnUYWKzIKdOgPCl70vuGQU9t5wlg_MCEgqcLJk9C6YpvD2hPZV-TQ0xKw2ZnKHG3wM-4KXxTd4Z/pubchart?oid=993832988&amp;amp;format=image&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;captions&quot;&gt;
This chart shows the trend of total P-R apportionment per fiscal year, from 1979 to 1988.&lt;br /&gt;
(Data via &lt;a href=&quot;https://wsfrprograms.fws.gov/Subpages/GrantPrograms/WR/WR_Funding.htm&quot;&gt;USFWS&lt;/a&gt;)
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;881.5888697855398&quot; height=&quot;503&quot; seamless=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/e/2PACX-1vRQdMnUYWKzIKdOgPCl70vuGQU9t5wlg_MCEgqcLJk9C6YpvD2hPZV-TQ0xKw2ZnKHG3wM-4KXxTd4Z/pubchart?oid=1956450952&amp;amp;format=image&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;captions&quot;&gt;
This chart shows the trend of total P-R apportionment per fiscal year, from 1989 to 1998.&lt;br /&gt;
(Data via &lt;a href=&quot;https://wsfrprograms.fws.gov/Subpages/GrantPrograms/WR/WR_Funding.htm&quot;&gt;USFWS&lt;/a&gt;)
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;881.5888697855398&quot; height=&quot;503&quot; seamless=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/e/2PACX-1vRQdMnUYWKzIKdOgPCl70vuGQU9t5wlg_MCEgqcLJk9C6YpvD2hPZV-TQ0xKw2ZnKHG3wM-4KXxTd4Z/pubchart?oid=300093849&amp;amp;format=image&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;captions&quot;&gt;
This chart shows the trend of total P-R apportionment per fiscal year, from 1999 to 2008.&lt;br /&gt;
(Data via &lt;a href=&quot;https://wsfrprograms.fws.gov/Subpages/GrantPrograms/WR/WR_Funding.htm&quot;&gt;USFWS&lt;/a&gt;)
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/secretary-zinke-announces-more-that-11-billion-sportsmen-conservation&quot;&gt;Secretary Zinke Announces More Than $1.1 Billion for Sportsmen &amp;amp; Conservation&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.perc.org/2015/01/20/paying-to-play-in-the-great-outdoors/&quot;&gt;Paying to Play in the Great Outdoors&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 00:37:26 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/02/17/conservation-and-hunting/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/02/17/conservation-and-hunting/</guid>
        
        <category>conservation</category>
        
        <category>hunting</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Site Revamp</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Technology is like fashion, trends will come and go. You might be wondering, how
do I know whether it is time to revamp my website? The answer can differ, but
it’s essential for your website to be as up-to-date and functional as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s 9 indicators that point to a revamp:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nonresponsive Site or Mobile-Unfriendly&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Slow Load Time&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Crowded Pages&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Absence of a Content Management System (CMS)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;High Bounce Rate&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Low Conversion Rate&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your Site Uses Flash&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Outdated Content and Images&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Low Search Rankings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the last real revamp/refresh of my site was on Jul 21, 2017. Now that doesn’t
seem like a long time ago but it was. If I use the indicators listed above as a
guide I was hitting 4/9 indicators. That seems to me like an effort worth
undertaking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I started reworking the site a week or so ago and here we are today. With the
old site looking pretty dated and wanting to take advantage of some new jekyll
plugins I have a new site launched. I really do prefer this look and feel over
the old site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the features of the old site have not yet been transferred over so
please bear with me. If you notice something horribly broken please let me know.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 08:28:17 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/02/15/site-revamp/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/02/15/site-revamp/</guid>
        
        <category>blogging</category>
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>